today we have Josh Tenenbaum he's a
今天我们有Josh Tenenbaum 他是一个
professor here at MIT leading the
这里的教授在 麻省理工学院 领导
computational cognitive science group
计算认知科学小组
among many other topics and cognition
在众多其他主题和认知中
and intelligence he is fascinated with
和他所着迷的情报
the question of how human beings learn
人类如何学习的问题
so much from so little and how these
这么多， 以及如何这些
insights can lead to build AI systems
洞察力可以导致构建AI系统
that are much more efficient at learning
学习效率更高
from data so please give Josh a warm
从数据，所以请给乔希一个温暖
welcome all right thank you very much
欢迎你，非常感谢你
thanks for having me decided to be part
谢谢你让我决定参与其中
of what looks like really quite a very
看起来真的非常非常
impressive lineup especially starting
令人印象深刻的阵容特别是 首发
after today and it's I think quite a
在今天之后，我认为这是相当的
great opportunity to get to see
很好的机会， 能看到
perspectives on artificial intelligence
关于人工智能的观点
from many of the leaders in industry and
来自许多工业领域的领导者
other entities working on this this
其他正在研究此事的实体
great quest so I'm going to talk to you
伟大的追求，所以我要跟 你说话
about some of the work that we do in our
关于我们在我们 的工作中 所做的一些工作
group but also I'm gonna try to give a
小组， 但 我也会 尝试给一个
broader perspective reflective of a
更广泛的视角反映了一个
number of MIT faculty especially those
麻省理工学院的教师数量， 特别是那些
who are affiliated with the Center for
谁是隶属于 中心
brains minds and machines so you can see
脑子和机器，所以你可以看到
up there on my affiliation academically
在学术上我的联盟
I'm part of brain and cognitive science
我是大脑和认知科学的一部分
or course nine I'm also part of csail
或者当然， 我也是csail的一部分
but I'm also part of the Center for
但我也是该 中心的一部分
brains minds and machines which is an
大脑的头脑 和机器是一个
NSF funded Center Science and Technology
NSF资助的中心科学与技术
Center which really stands for the
中心， 该中心确实 代表了
bridge between the science and the
科学与科学之间的桥梁
engineering of intelligence
智力工程
it literally straddles Vassar Street and
它实际上横跨Vassar街和
that we have csail and DCs members we
我们有 csail和DCs成员我们
also have partners at Harvard and other
在哈佛和其他地方也有合作伙伴
academic institutions and again what we
学术机构 和我们再一次
stand for I want to try to convey some
代表 我想尝试传达一些
of the specific things we're doing in
具体 的事情，我们正在做 的
the center and where we want to go with
中心和我们想去的地方
a vision that really is about jointly
一个真正关于共同的愿景
pursuing the science the basic science
追求科学的基础科学
of how intelligence arises in the human
智力如何在人类中产生
mind and brain and also the engineering
思想和大脑以及 工程学
enterprise of how to build something
企业如何建立一些东西
increasingly like human intelligence in
越来越像人类的智慧
machines and we deeply believe that
机器，我们 深信
these two projects have something to do
这两个项目有一些事情要做
with each other and our best pursued
彼此和我们最好的追求
jointly now it's really exciting time to
现在，这是非常激动人心的 时刻
be doing anything related to
做任何与之相关的事情
intelligence or certainly to AI for all
对 所有人来说， 智能或人工智能
the reasons that you know brought you
你知道的原因给 你带来了什么
all here I don't have to tell you this
在这里，我没有告诉你这一点
we have all these ways in which AI is
我们拥有AI的所有这些方式
kind of finally here we finally live in
那种 终于来了，我们终于住
the era of something like real practical
真实实用的时代
AI
AI
or for those who've been around for a
或者那些曾经去过的人
while and have seen some of the rises
虽然 并且看到了一些 升起
and falls you know AI is back in a big
你知道AI 已经回归了
way but from my perspective and I think
方式， 但从 我的角度来看，我认为
maybe this reflects you know why we
也许这反映了你知道我们为什么
distinguish what we might call a GI from
区分我们可能称之为GI的东西
AI we we don't really have any real AI
我们，我们 真的没有真正的人工智能
basically we have what I like to call AI
基本上我们有什么我 喜欢 叫AI
technologies which are systems that do
技术这是做系统
things we used to think that only humans
我们曾经认为只有人类的东西
could do and now we have machines that
可以做，现在我们有机器
do them often quite well maybe even
他们经常做得很好甚至可能
better than any human who's ever lived
比 任何 曾经生活过的 人 都要好
right like a machine that plays go but
就像一台可以玩的机器一样
none of these systems I would say are
我不会说这些系统
truly intelligent none of them have
真正聪明的没有 人
anything like common sense none of them
任何像常识一样的东西都没有
have anything like the flexible
有灵活的东西
general-purpose intelligence that each
每个人的通用情报
of you might use to learn every one of
你可能会用来 学习每一个
these skills or tasks right each of
这些技能或任务各自正确
these systems had to be built by large
这些系统必须由大型建造
teams of engineers working together
工程师团队一起工作
often for a number of years out often at
经常在很多 年 里 经常出现
great cost to somebody who's willing to
对于愿意的人来说，这是一笔巨大的成本
pay for it and each of them just does
支付它，而且每个人都 这样做
one thing so alphago might beat the
有一件事，所以alphago可能击败了
worlds best but it can't drive to the
世界上最好的 ，但它不能开车到
match or even tell you that go it what
匹配甚至告诉你，它去做什么
go is it can't even tell you the go is a
走的是它甚至不能告诉你 走的是一个
game because it doesn't even know what a
游戏， 因为它甚至不知道什么
game is right so what's missing why what
游戏是对的，所以什么错过了为什么
what is it that makes every one of your
什么使 你的 每一 个人
brains maybe you can't beat you know the
也许你不能打败你知道的大脑
world's best didn't go but any one of
世界上最好的没有去， 但任何一个
you can get behind the wheel of a car I
你可以坐在汽车的车轮后面
think of this because my daughter is
想到这一点，因为我的女儿是
gonna turn 16 tomorrow if she lived in
如果她住在 明天会明天16岁
California she'd have a driver's license
加利福尼亚州她有驾驶执照
it's a little bit down the line for us
这 对我们来说 有点下线
here in Massachusetts but you know she
在马萨诸塞州，但你知道她
didn't have to be specially engineered
没有特别设计
by billion dollar startups and you know
十亿美元的初创公司，你知道
she got really into chess recently and
她最近和国际象棋有了很大的关系
now she's taught herself chess by
现在她自学了国际象棋
playing just you know a handful of games
只是你玩了 一些游戏
basically I mean she can do any one of
基本上我是说 她可以做 的 任何一个
these activities and any one of us can
这些活动和 我们 任何一个 人都可以
so what is it what's that what makes up
那么究竟是什么构成的 呢？
the difference well there's many things
差异很大，有很多东西
right I'll talk about the the focus for
好吧， 我会谈论 的焦点
us and our research and a lot of us
我们和我们的研究以及我们很多人
again in CBMM is summarized here um what
再次在CBMM中总结一下这是什么
what drives the success is right now in
现在是什么推动了成功
AI especially in industry okay and all
人工智能特别是在行业中还可以
these AI technologies is many many
这些人工智能技术有很多种
things many things but what's what where
事情很多 事情 ，但什么是什么地方
the progress has been made most recently
最近 取得了进展
and what's getting most of the attention
什么得到了大部分的关注
is of course deep learning but other
当然是深度学习， 但其他
kinds of machine learning technologies
各种机器学习技术
which essentially represent the
这基本上代表了
maturation of a decades-long
几十年的成熟
for to solve the problem of pattern
用于解决模式问题
recognition that means taking data and
识别， 这 意味着取数据和
finding patterns in the data that tells
找到告诉 的数据 中的 模式
you something you care about like how to
你关心的事情 如何
label a class or how to predict some
标记一个类或如何预测一些
other signal okay
其他信号没关系
and pattern recognition is great it's an
和模式识别是伟大的它是一个
important part of intelligence and it's
智力的重要组成部分 ，它的
reasonable to say the deep learning as a
合理的说 深刻的学习 是一种
technology has really made great strides
技术确实取得了长足的进步
on pattern recognition and maybe even
关于模式识别甚至可能
you know has coming close to solving the
你知道已接近解决问题
problems of pattern recognition but
模式识别的问题但是
intelligence is about many other things
情报是关于许多其他事情
intelligence is about a lot more in
情报是关于 更多的
particular it's about modeling the world
特别是关于建模世界
and think about all the activities that
并考虑所有的活动
a human does so model the world that
人类确实为这个世界建模
that go beyond just say recognizing
超越 只是说认识
patterns and data but actually trying to
模式和数据， 但实际上尝试
explain and understand what we see for
解释并理解我们所看到的
instance okay or to be able to imagine
例如 正确的， 或者是 能够 想象
things that we've never seen that never
我们 从未见过的事情 从未如此
seen maybe even very different from
看到甚至 可能 非常不同
anything we've ever seen but might want
我们见过但 可能想要的任何东西
to see and then to meet to set those as
看到然后见面设置那些
goals to make plans and solve problems
制定计划和解决问题的目标
needed to make those things real or
需要让这些东西真实或
thinking about learning again the you
想着再次学习你
know some kinds of learning can be
知道某种学习方式可以
thought of as pattern recognition if
如果被认为是模式识别
you're learning sufficient statistics or
你正在学习足够的统计数据或
weights in a neural net that are used
使用的神经网络中的权重
for those purposes but many activities
出于这些目的， 但许多活动
of learning are about building out new
学习是关于建立新的
models right either refining reusing
模型可以改进重复使用
improving old models or actually
改进旧模型或实际上
building fundamentally new models as
从根本上建立新模式
you've experienced more of the world and
你已经经历了 更多 的世界和
then think about sharing our models
然后考虑分享 我们的模型
communicating our models to others
将我们的模型传达给他人
modeling their models learning from them
建模他们的模型从中学习
all these activities of modeling these
所有这些 建模 活动
are at the heart of human intelligence
是人类智慧的核心
and it requires a much broader set of
它需要更广泛的一套
tools so I want to talk about the ways
工具所以我想谈谈 这些方法
we're studying these activities of
我们正在研究这些活动
modeling the world and something in a
造型在世界上有什么东西
pretty non-technical way about what are
关于什么是非技术性的方式
the kind of tools that allow us to
那种允许 我们使用的工具
capture these abilities now I think it's
现在我认为这是捕捉这些能力 的
I want to be very honest up front and to
我想在前面和前面说实话
say this is just the beginning of a
说这是 一个 刚刚 开始
story right when you look at deep
当你深入地看时，故事就是正确的
learning successes that itself is a
学习成功本身就是一个
story that goes back decades I'll say a
几十年前的故事，我会说一个
little bit about that history in a
有关 在 历史 点点
minute but where we are now is just
分钟， 但我们 现在只是
looking forward to a future when we
期待我们的未来
might be able to capture these abilities
也许能够 捕捉到这些能力
you know at a really mature engineering
你知道一个非常成熟的工程
scale and I would say we are far from
规模，我会说我们远离
being able to capture the all the ways
能够捕捉到所有的方法
in which humans richly flexibly quickly
人类富有灵活的快速
build models of the world at the kind of
建立世界模型的那种
scale that say Silicon Valley wants
说硅谷想要的 规模
either big tech companies like Google or
无论是Google还是Google等大型科技公司
soft or IBM or Facebook or small
软或IBM或Facebook或小型
startups right we can get there and I
创业公司， 我们可以到达那里，我
think what what I want to talk to you
想想我想跟你说些什么
about here is one route for trying to
关于这里是尝试的一条路线
get there and this is the route that
到达那里，这是路线
CBMM stands for the idea that by reverse
CBMM代表 反向 的想法
engineering how intelligence works in
设计智能如何工作
the human mind and brain that will give
将给予的人类思想和 大脑
us a route to engineering these
我们是 设计这些工程 的途径
abilities in machines when we say
我们说的时候机器的能力
reverse engineering we're talking about
我们正在谈论的逆向工程
science but doing science like engineers
科学，但像工程师一样做科学
this is our fundamental principle that
这是我们的基本原则
if we approach cognitive science and
如果我们接近认知科学和
neuroscience like an engineer where so
神经像一个工程师 ，所以
the output of our science isn't just a
我们的科学 的输出不只是一个
description of the brain or the mind in
大脑或心灵的说明
words but in the same terms that an
单词，但用相同的术语 表示
engineer would use to build an
工程师会用来建立一个
intelligence system then that will be
情报系统那将是
both the basis for a much more rigorous
两者都是更加严谨的基础
and deeply insightful science but also
而且深刻有见地的科学也
direct translation of those insights
直接翻译那些见解
into engineering applications
进入工程应用
now I said before I talk a little about
现在我在谈谈之前说过
history what I mean by that is is this
历史我的意思是这个
again if if part of what brought you
再次，如果是什么部分带给 你
here is deep learning and I know even if
这是深度 学习 ，我知道即使
you've never heard of deep learning
你从来没有听说过深度学习
before which I'm sure is unlikely you
在此之前，我确定你不太可能
saw some you know a good spectrum of
看到一些你知道的很好
that in the in the overview session last
在最后的概述会话中
night okay it's really interesting and
晚上好，这真的很有趣
important to look back on the history of
重要的是要回顾 历史
where did techniques for deep learning
哪里有深度学习的技巧
come from or reinforcement learning
来自或加强学习
those are the two tools in the in the
那些是中的两个工具
current machine learning arsenal that
当前的机器学习武器库
are getting the most attention things
是最受 关注的事情
like back propagation or end to end
像反向传播或端到端
stochastic gradient descent or temporal
随机梯度下降或时间
difference learning or cue learning
差异学习或提示 学习
here's a few papers from the literature
这里有一些文献中 的文章
you know maybe some of you have read
你知道也许有些人已经读过了
these original papers here's here's the
这些原始论文就在这里
original paper by rumelhart Hinton and
rumelhart Hinton 和
colleagues in which they introduced the
他们介绍的同事
back propagation algorithm for training
训练的 反向 传播算法
multi-layer perceptrons right
多层感知器正确
multi-layer neural networks here's the
这里有多层神经网络
original perceptron paper by Rosenblatt
Rosenblatt撰写的原始感知纸
which introduced the one layer version
它引入了一层版本
of that architecture and the basic
那个架构和基础
perceptron learning algorithm here's the
感知器学习算法在这里
first paper on sort of the temporal
关于 时间性的 第一篇论文
difference learning method for
差异学习方法
reinforcement learning from Sutton and
萨顿和萨顿的强化学习
Bartow here's the original Bolton
巴托在这里是最初的博尔顿
machine paper also by Hinton and
机器纸也是由Hinton和
colleagues which you know again is a
你又知道的同事是一个
those you don't know that architecture
那些你不了解 建筑的人
they give a kind of probabilistic
他们给出了 一种 概率
undirected multi-layer perceptron or for
无向多层感知器 或 用于
example before there were LS TMS if you
如果你有LS TMS 之前的 例子
know about current recurrent neural
了解当前的反复神经
network architecture earlier as much
网络架构早一点
simpler versions of the same idea were
更简单的相同想法的版本
proposed by Jeff Elman and his simple
杰夫埃尔曼提出的 他和他的简单
recurrent networks the reason I want to
经常性网络我想要的原因
put up the original papers here
在这里搭起了 原始论文
for you to look at both when they were
让你看看它们的时间
published and where they were published
出版和出版地点
so if you look at the dates you'll see
所以，如果你看看 你会看到 的日期
papers going back to you know the the
回到你的论文知道了
80s but even the 60s or even the 1950s
80年代，甚至60年代甚至20世纪50年代
and look at where they were published
看看他们发表的地方
most of them were published in
其中大部分都是 在
psychology journals so the journal
心理学期刊所以期刊
psychological review if you don't know
心理审查， 如果你不知道
it is like the leading journal of
它就像是领先的期刊
theoretical psychology and mathematical
理论心理学与数学
psychology okay or cognitive science the
心理学好或认知科学
Journal of the cognitive science Society
认知 科学学会 期刊
or the the backdrop paper was published
或背景文件发表
in Nature which is a general interest
在大自然 中是一般兴趣
science journal but by people who are
作者：但人 谁是
mostly affiliated with an Institute for
主要隶属于研究所
cognitive science in San Diego so what
圣地亚哥的认知科学是什么
you see here is already a long history
你看这里已经有很长的历史了
of scientists thinking like engineers
像工程师一样思考的科学家
these are people who are in psychology
这些人都是 心理学家
or cognitive science departments and
或认知科学系和
publishing in those places but by
在那些地方出版但是通过
formalizing even very basic insights
形式化甚至非常基本的见解
about how humans might learn or how you
关于人类如何 学习或如何学习
know brains might learn in the right
知道大脑可能会在右边学习
kind of math that led to of course
当然 导致了一种数学
progress on the science side but it led
科学方面取得了进展，但却取得了进展
to all the engineering that we see now
我们现在看到的所有工程
it wasn't sufficient right we needed we
这是不够 的权利 ，我们需要我们
needed of course lots of innovations and
当然需要大量 的创新和
advances in computing hardware and
计算硬件和计算机的进步
software systems right but this is where
软件系统正确， 但这是在哪里
the basic the basic math came from and
基础数学来自和
it came from doing science like an
它来自做科学就像一个
engineer so what I want to talk about in
工程师所以我想要谈论的内容
our vision is what is the future of this
我们的愿景是什么是未来
look like if we were to look 50 years
看起来好像我们要看50年
into the future what would we be looking
未来我们 将会 看到 什么
back on now or you know over this time
回到 现在 还是你知道这段 时间
scale well here's that here's a
这里的 规模 很大， 这是 一个
long-term research roadmap that reflects
反映的长期研究路线图
some of my ambitions and some of our
我的 一些抱负 和我们的一些
centers goals and many others too right
中心目标和许多其他目标 太 对了
we'd like to be able to address basic
我们希望能够解决基本问题
questions fundamental questions of what
质疑什么是基本问题
it is to be and to think like a human
它应该像人一样思考
questions for example of consciousness
例如意识的问题
or meaning in language or real learning
或意思是语言或真正的学习
right questions like you know even
像你这样的正确问题
beyond the individual like questions of
超越个人喜欢的问题
culture or creativity so our big ideas
文化或创造力所以我们的重要思想
up there and for each of these there are
那里，对于这些有
basic scientific questions right how do
基本科学问题怎么做
we become aware of the world in
我们开始 意识到世界
ourselves in it starts with perception
我们自己从感知开始
but it really turns into awareness
但它真的 变成 了意识
awareness of yourself and of the world
对自己 和世界的 认识
and what we might call consciousness
我们可能称之为意识
right or how does a word start to have a
对，或一个单词如何开始有一个
meaning what really is a meaning and how
意味着什么是真正的意义 和方式
does a child grasp it or how did
孩子能抓住它 或者怎么做
children actually learn what do babies
孩子们实际上学习了 什么 做婴儿
brains actually start with are they
大脑实际上是 从他们开始的
blank slates or do they start with some
空白的石板或他们从 一些 开始
kind of cognitive structure and then
一种认知结构， 然后
what is real learning look like these
什么是真正的学习看起来像这些
are just some of the questions that were
都 只是一些 人 的问题
we're interested in working on
我们感兴趣的工作
or when we talked about culture we mean
或者当我们谈论文化时我们的意思
how do you learn all the things you
你怎么了解你的所有 事情
didn't directly experience right but
没有直接体验的权利 ，但
that somehow you got from the
不知怎的，你是从那里得到的
accumulation of knowledge in society
知识在社会 中积累
over many generations or how do you ever
多代人 或你怎么 做过
think of new ideas or answers to new
想到新的想法或新的答案
questions how do you think of the new
问你怎么 看待新的
questions themselves how do you decide
问自己你是如何决定的
what to think about these are all key
怎么想 这些都是 关键
activities of human intelligence when we
我们的人类智慧活动
talk about how we model the world where
谈谈我们如何模拟世界 在哪里
our models come from what we do with our
我们的模型来自我们对我们的 所作所为
models this is what we're talking about
模特这就是我们 所说的
and if we could get machines that could
如果我们能得到可以的机器
do these things well again on the bottom
在底部再次做好这些事情
row think of all the actual real
排想到所有真实的
engineering payoffs now in our Center in
现在在我们中心的工程收益
both my own activities and a lot of what
我自己的活动和 很多什么
my group does these days and what a
这些天我的小组做了什么
number of other colleagues in the Center
该 中心 的其他 同事人数
for brains minds and machines do as well
对于大脑而言，思想和机器也是如此
as you know brought very broadly people
如你所知，带来了非常广泛的人
in VCS and csail one place where we work
在VCS和csail我们工作的地方
on the beginnings of these problems in
在这些问题的开始
the near term this is the long term like
近期这是长期的
think 50 years okay maybe short or maybe
认为50年好吧可能很短或者也许
longer I don't know but think well
更长的我 不知道，但想好
beyond well beyond 10 years but in the
超过10年但超过10年
short term 5 to 10 years a lot of our
很短的 5到10年我们很多
focus is around visual intelligence and
重点是视觉智能和
there's many reasons for that again we
再有就是很多原因， 我们
can build on the successes of deep
可以建立在深刻的成功基础之上
networks and a lot of pattern
网络和很多模式
recognition and machine vision it's a
识别和 机器 视觉是一个
good way to put these ideas into
把这些 想法付诸实践的好方法
practice when we when we look at the
实践中，我们的时候，当我们 在看
actual brain the visual system in the
实际大脑中的视觉系统
brain in the human and other mammalian
人类和其他哺乳动物的大脑
brains for example is really very
例如，大脑真的很棒
clearly the best understood part of the
显然是最了解的部分
brain and at a circuit level it's the
大脑和电路级别是
part of the brain that's most inspired
最受启发 的大脑 的 一部分
current deep learning and neural network
目前的深度学习和 神经网络
systems but even there there's things
系统，但即使有那些东西
which we still don't really understand
我们仍然不太懂
like engineers so here's an example of a
像工程师所以这里的一个例子
basic problem in visual intelligence
视觉智能的基本问题
that we and others in the centre are
我们和中心的其他人都是
trying to solve look around you and you
试着解决你周围的问题
feel like there's a whole world around
感觉 周围 有一个整个世界
you and there is a whole world around
你和 周围 有 一个世界
you feel like your brain captures it but
你觉得你的大脑抓住了它
what what the actual sense data that's
那是什么实际意义数据
coming in through your eyes looks more
通过你的眼睛进来看起来更多
like this photograph here where you can
像这张照片在这里你可以
see there's a crowd scene but it's
看到有一个人群场景，但它是
mostly blurry except for a small region
除了一个小区域，大多模糊
of high resolution in the center so that
在中心的高分辨率， 以便
corresponds biologically to what part of
在生物学上对应于什么部分
the images in your fovea that's the
在你的中央凹的图像是
central region of cells in the retina
视网膜 细胞的 中央 区域
where you have really high-resolution
你真的有高分辨率的地方
visual data the size of your phobia is
您的恐惧症大小的视觉数据
roughly like if you hold out your thumb
就像你伸出拇指一样
at arm's length it's a little bit bigger
在一定距离， 它有点大
than that but not much bigger right
比那更大 但 没有 更大的权利
most of the image in terms of the actual
大多数图像就实际而言
information coming in and a bottom-up
信息进入 和自下而上
sense to your brain is really quite
你的大脑感觉真的很好
blurry
模糊
but somehow by looking at just one part
但不知何故， 只看一部分
and then by secada around or making a
然后由 secada环绕或 制作一个
few eye movements you get a few glimpses
很少有眼球运动你会得到一些瞥见
each not much bigger than the size of
每个都不比大小大
your thumb at arm's length
你的拇指在手臂的长度
somehow you stitch that information
不知怎的，你缝了那些信息
together into what feels like and really
一起感觉和真的
is a rich representation of the whole
是一个丰富的整体代表
world around you and when I say around
你 周围的世界和 我说的时候
you I mean literally around you so
你我的意思就是在你周围
here's another kind of demonstration um
这是另一种示范嗯
without turning around nobody's allowed
没有转过身就没有人允许
to turn around ask yourself what's
转身问自己是什么
behind you now the answer is going to be
在你身后现在的答案是
different for different people depending
因人而异
on where you're sitting right for most
在哪里你 坐在正确 的最
of you you might think well there's I
你可能认为我就是你
think there's a person pretty close
认为 有一个人非常接近
behind me all right you know you're in a
在 我 身后， 你 知道你在
crowded auditorium although you haven't
拥挤的礼堂，虽然你没有
seen that person you know that they're
看到那个 你 知道 他们的人
there right for people in the very back
有适合后面的人
row you know there isn't a person behind
你知道 后面 没有一个人
you and you're conscious of being in the
你和 你意识到自己身处其中
back row right you might be conscious
你可能会有意识地向右排
that there's a wall right behind you but
你身后 有一堵墙 ，但是
now for the people who are in the room
现在是在房间里的人
not in the very back think about how far
不是在 后面想想 多远
behind you is the back like where's the
你身后的 背后就像 是在 哪里
nearest wall behind you so we can get
离你最近的墙，所以我们可以得到
maybe we can call out try a little
也许我们可以打电话 试试一下
demonstration so I don't know I'm
示威，所以我不知道我
pointing to someone there can you see
指着某人，你能看到吗？
phrase say something if you think I'm
如果你 认为我是 这样的话
pointing at you well I could have been
指着你还有我本来可以
pointing at you but I'm pointing someone
指着你，但我指着某人
behind you okay I'll point to you yeah
在你身后好吧我会指向你是的
I'm pointing to you all right
我正指着你
so how far is the nearest wall no you
所以离 你 最近的墙 有 多远
can't turn around you've blown your
无法转身你已经吹了你的
chance right without turning around okay
机会权利 ，没有 好的起色
so you you were laughs okay do you see
所以，你笑了，你看到了吗？
I'm pointing to you there with the tie
我带着领带指着你
okay so without turning around how far
好的，所以没有转身多远
is the nearest wall behind you that's
是你身后最近的墙
sorry how far five meters okay well I
对不起我五米多好吧
mean that might be about right no other
意味着可能与 其他人无关
people can turn around how about you how
人们可以转过身来 怎么样
far is the nearest wall behind you
远离你最近的墙
ten meters okay that might be right yeah
十米好吧 ，这可能 是对的，是的
how about here
这边怎么样
how what do you think twenty okay see
你觉得 二十 好 怎么 看？
yeah since I didn't grow up in the
是的，因为我没有长大的
metric system I barely know but yeah I
公制我几乎不知道，但是我
mean I mean the point is that like
意思是我的意思是说点 就像
you're you're you each of you is is not
你是你，你们每个 人都不是
surely not exactly right but you're
肯定不完全正确， 但 你是
certainly within an order of magnitude
当然在一个数量级内
and I guess if we actually tried to
我想如果我们真的尝试过
measure you know you're probably my
衡量你知道你可能是我的
guess is you're probably right within
猜猜你可能是对的
you know fifty percent or less often you
你知道百分之 五十 以下的时候 ，你
know maybe just twenty percent error
知道可能只有20％的错误
okay so how do you know this I mean even
好吧你怎么知道这个 我的意思是 甚至
if it's not what did you say twenty
如果不是你说的那么 二十
meters even if it's not twenty meters
米， 即使 不是二十米
it's probably closer to 20 meters than
它可能比20米更接近
it is to 5 or 10 meters and then it is
它是 5或 10 米，那么它是
250 meters so how do you know this you
250 米所以你怎么知道这个你
haven't turned around in a while right
在一段时间没有转头 向右
but some part of your brain is tracking
但是 大脑的 某些部分 正在跟踪
the whole world around you right and how
你身边的整个世界都是正确的
many people are behind you yeah like a
很多人 都 在你身后，是 的
few hundred right I mean I don't know if
几百对，我的 意思是我不知道是否
it's 200 or 300 or but it's not a
它是200或300或者它不是
thousand I mean I don't think so and
千我的意思是，我不 这么认为
it's certainly not ten or 20 or 50 right
它当然不是 10 或 20或50对
so you track these things and you use
所以你跟踪这些东西 并使用
them to plan your actions
他们计划你的 行动
okay so again think about how instantly
好吧再这么想想
effortlessly and very reliably okay your
毫不费力，非常可靠地好 你的
brain computes all these things so the
大脑计算所有这些东西， 所以
people and objects around you and it's
你周围的 人和物体
not just you know approximations
不只是你知道近似值
certainly when we're talking about
当然，当我们谈论
what's what's behind you in space
在太空中你背后的是什么
there's a lot of imprecision but when it
有很多不精确但是当它
comes to reaching for things right in
来到了正确 的事物
front of you
在你面前
very precise shape and physical property
非常精确的形状和物理特性
estimates needed to pick up and
估计需要提升和
manipulate objects and then when it
操纵对象然后何时操作
comes to people it's not just the
来到人们这 不仅仅是
existence of the people but something
人的存在但是有些东西
about what's in their head right you
关于你头脑中的事情
track whether someone's paying attention
追踪是否有人在关注
to you and you're talking to them what
对你而言，你正在 和 他们 说话
they might want from you what they might
他们可能想要你能得到什么
be thinking about you what they might be
想着 你 ，他们可能是什么
thinking about other people okay so when
在考虑 其他 人的时候还好吧
we talk about visual intelligence this
我们谈论的视觉智能 本
is the whole stuff we're talking about
是我们谈论的东西全
and you can start to see how it turns
你 可以开始看看 它是如何转变的
into basic questions I think of not of
我想到的基本问题不是
what we might call the beginnings of
我们可能称之为的开头
consciousness at least our awareness of
意识，至少我们的意识
ourself in the world and of ourselves as
在 世界和 我们自己
a self in the world but also other
世界上的自我， 也是其他人
aspects of higher-level intelligence and
更高层次的 情报和方面
cognition that are not just about
不仅仅是认知
perception like symbols right to
知觉一样有权符号
describe even to ourselves what's around
甚至向我们自己描述周围的事物
us and where we are and what we can do
我们和我们 在 哪里 以及我们能做些什么
with it
用它
you have to go beyond just what we would
你必须超越我们的意愿
normally call the stuff of perception to
通常称之为 感知 的 东西
say the thoughts in somebody's head and
说在别人的头的想法 和
your own thoughts about that okay so
关于 你自己的想法 好 了，
what we've been doing in CBMM is trying
我们 在CBMM所做的就是尝试
to develop an architecture for visual
开发视觉架构
intelligence and I'm not going to go
情报 ，我不会去
into any of the details of how this
到任何的 如何 的细节
works and this is just notional this is
工作， 这只是概念
just a picture it's like a just a sketch
只是一张图片就像一张草图
from a grant proposal of what we say we
来自我们所说的我们的拨款提案
want to do but it's based on a lot of
想要做的，但它是基于大量 的
scientific understanding of how the
科学地了解 如何
brain works there are different parts of
大脑工作有不同的部分
the brain that correspond to these
与这些相对应的大脑
different modules in our architecture as
在 我们的架构不同的模块
well as some kind of emerging
以及某种新兴的
engineering way to try to capture at the
工程的方式，试图在捕捉
software and maybe even hardware levels
软件， 甚至硬件水平
how these modules might work so we talk
这些模块如何工作，所以我们 谈谈
about a sort of an early module of a
关于某种 早期模块
visual or perceptual stream which
视觉或感知流
like bottom-up visual or other
喜欢自下而上的视觉或其他
perceptual input that's the kind of
感知输入就是那种
thing that is pretty close to what we
与 我们 非常接近的事情
currently have and say deep
目前已经并且说得很深
convolutional neural networks but then
然后是卷积神经网络
we talk about some kind of the output of
我们谈论某种输出
that isn't just pattern class labels but
这不仅仅是 模式类标签
what we call the cognitive core core
我们称之为认知核心核心
cognition so we get an understanding of
认知， 所以我们了解
space and objects there physics
空间和物体 有物理学
other people their minds that's the real
其他人他们的想法是真实的
stuff of cognition that has to be the
认知的东西必须是
output of perception but somehow we have
感知的输出但我们有某种方式
to we have we have to have this is what
我们必须 拥有这是什么
we call the brain OS in this picture we
我们在这张照片中称之为脑OS
have to get there by stitching together
必须通过 缝合在一起
the bottom-up inputs from glimpse here a
从 这里 窥见 一个 自下而上的投入
glimpse here a little bit here and there
瞥见这里和那里一点点
and accessing prior knowledge that comes
和访问 自带 先验知识
from our memory systems to tell us how
从我们的记忆系统告诉我们如何
to stitch these things together into the
把这些东西缝合在一起
really core cognitive representations of
真正的核心认知表征
what's out there in the world and then
那时候世界上有什么呢？
if we're going to start to talk about it
如果我们要开始谈论它
in language or to build plans on top of
在语言或建立计划 之上
what we have seen and understood that's
我们所看到和理解的 是什么
where we talk about symbols coming into
在那里我们谈论进入的 符号
the picture ok the building blocks of
图片确定了构建基块
language and plans and so on so now we
语言和计划等 现在我们
might say well ok this is an
可能会说 好，这是一个
architecture that is brain inspired and
建筑是大脑的启发和
cognitively inspired and and we're
认知灵感，我们是
planning to turn into real engineering
计划变成 真正的工程
and you can say well do we need that
你可以说 做的 好 ，我们需要的是
maybe you know again I know this is a
也许你又知道我知道这是一个
question you considered in the first
你 在第一次 考虑的 问题
lecture
演讲
maybe the engineering toolkit that's
也许是工程工具包
currently been making a lot of progress
目前取得了很大进展
in let's say industry maybe that's good
让我们说工业也许这很好
enough maybe you know let's take deep
也许你 知道让我们深入了解
learning but to stand for a broader set
学习， 但 要站在更广泛的地位
of modern pattern recognition based and
现代模式识别的基础与方法
reinforcement learning based tools and
基于强化学习的工具和
say ok well maybe that can scale up to
说好的也许可以扩展 到
this and you might you know it but maybe
这个，你可能知道但也许
that's that's possible I'm happy in the
那是可能的，我很高兴
question period of people want to debate
问题期间人们想辩论
this my sense is no I think that it's
这是我的感觉是 不，我认为这是
not when I say no I don't mean like it
不是我说没有我的意思不是喜欢它
can't happen or it won't happen what I
不会发生或不会发生我的事
mean is the highest value the highest
平均值是最高值
expected route right now is to take this
现在的 预期 路线 是采取 这个
more science-based reverse engineering
更多基于科学的逆向工程
approach and that if at least if you
方法， 如果至少如果你
follow the current trajectory that
遵循当前的轨迹
industry incentives especially optimized
行业激励特别优化
for it's not even really trying to take
因为它甚至没有真正尝试
us to these things so think about for
我们对这些事情如此思考
example a case study of visual
例如 视觉 案例研究
intelligence that is in some ways as
在某些方面的情报
pattern recognition very much of a
模式识别非常多
success it's again been mostly driven by
成功 它再次主要 是由
industry it's something that if you read
如果你读的话，这就是行业
in the
在里面
Jews or even play around with in certain
犹太人 甚至 在某些地方 玩耍
of it publicly available datasets feels
它公开 可用的 数据集 感觉
like we've made great progress and this
就像我们已经取得了很大的进步 ，这
is an aspect of visual intelligence
是视觉 智能的一个方面
which is sometimes called image
有时也称为图像
captioning it's bate or mapping images
标题是它的 bate或映射图像
to text you know basically there's been
文字你知道基本上已经有了
a bunch of systems here's a couple of
这里有一堆系统
press releases I guess this one's about
新闻稿我猜这个是关于
Google Google's AI can now capture
Google谷歌的人工智能现在可以捕获
images almost as well as humans
图像几乎和人类一样
here's ones about Microsoft a couple of
这里有关于微软的几个
years ago I think there were something
几年前我觉得 有些 东西
like eight papers all released onto
像 八篇论文全部发布 到
archive around the same time from
从 同一时间归档
basically all the major industry
基本上 所有的主要产业
computer vision groups as well as a
计算机视觉团体以及 一
couple of academic partners okay which
几个学术伙伴 好吗哪个
all driven by basically the same data
全部由基本相同的数据驱动
set produced by some Microsoft
一些 微软 制作的集合
researchers and other collaborators
研究人员和其他合作者
trained a combination of deep
训练了一个深刻的组合
convolutional neural networks you know
你知道的卷积神经网络
state of the art visual pattern
最先进的视觉模式
recognition with recurrent neural
复发神经网络识别
networks which had recently been
网络最近已
developed for you know basically kinds
开发你知道基本上 种
of neural statistical language modeling
神经统计语言建模
glued them together and produced a
将它们粘在一起并制成一个
system which which which made very
制作非常的系统
impressive results in a big training set
在一个大型训练集中取得了令人瞩
and a held-out test set where the goal
目标是一个坚持不懈的测试集
was to take an image and write a
是拍摄图像并写一个
sentence like a short sentence caption
句子就像一个简短的句子标题
that that would seem like the kind of
这看起来 像 那种
way a human would describe that image
人类会描述 那个形象的方式
and these systems you know surpassed
而这些你知道的系统超越了
human level accuracy on the held-out
持有 人的人员 准确度
test set from a big training set but
从一个大的训练集测试集 但是
what you can see when you really dig
当你真正挖掘时你 能 看到 什么
into these things is there's often a lot
进入这些事情往往是很多
of what I would call data set
我称之为 数据集
overfitting it's not overfitting to the
过度拟合它并不适合
training set but it's overfitting to
训练集，但它过度拟合
whatever are the particular
无论什么特别的
characteristics of this data set you
这个数据的特征设置你
know wherever ever came from certain set
知道从 哪里 某一组 取之不尽
of photographs and certain ways of
照片和某些方式
captioning them okay which even a big
说它们 还好，哪个都很大
data set it's not about quantity it's
数据集不是关于 它的 数量
more about the quality the nature of
更多关于质量的性质
what people are doing all right so one
什么人在 做 没事这样一个
way to test this system is to apply it
测试这个系统的方法是应用 它
to what seems like basically the same
看起来基本 相同
problem but not within the a certain
问题但不在一定范围内
curated or built data set and there's a
策划或建立数据集， 并有一个
convenient Twitter bot that lets you do
方便的Twitter机器人，让你做
this so there's something called the pic
这就是所谓的 pic
desk bot which takes one of the state of
服务器机器人采取的状态之一
the art industry AI captioning systems a
艺术行业AI字幕系统a
very good one again this is not meant to
非常好的再次这不是意味着
I'm not trying to critique these systems
我不是要批评这些系统
for what they're trying to do I'm just
对于他们想要做的事我只是
trying to point out what they don't
试图指出 他们没有
really even try to do so this takes the
真的，甚至尝试这样做，这需要
microsoft caption bot and just every
微软标题 机器人和每一个
couple of hours takes a random image
几个小时需要随机 图像
from the web captions it and upload
从网络标题和上传
the results to Twitter and a couple of
结果到Twitter和几个
months ago when I prepared a first
几个月前， 我准备了第一个
version of this talk I just took a few
这个讲话的版本我刚刚 拿了几个
days in the life of this Twitter bot I
这个Twitter机器人生命中的日子我
didn't take every single image but I
没有采取每一个图像， 但我
took you know most of the images in a
带你了解 大部分图片
way that was meant to be representative
这意味着具有代表性
of the successes and the kinds of
成功与种 的
failures that such a system will make so
这样的 系统将会失败
we can go through this and it's a little
我们可以通过这个， 这是一点点
bit entertaining and I think quite
有点 娱乐，我觉得 很好
informative so here's just a somewhat
提供信息所以这里只是 有点
random sample of a few days in the life
生活中几天的随机样本
of one of these caption BOTS so here we
其中一个 标题 BOTS所以我们这里
have a picture of a person holding for
有一个人 拿着一图片
tonight my screen is very small here and
今晚我的屏幕非常小
I can't read up there so maybe you'll
我不能读那里，所以也许你会
have to tell me was that but a person
不得不告诉我那是 一个人
holding a cell phone I guess I'll just
拿着手机， 我猜我会
read along with you so have a person
和 你一起读， 所以有一个人
holding a cell phone well it's not a
拿着手机很好，这不是一个
person holding a cell phone but it's
拿着手机的人却是
kind of close it's a person holding some
有点亲近它是一个持有一些人
kind of machine so I don't even know
那种机器 所以我甚至都不知道
what that is but it's some kind of
这是什么， 但它是某种
musical instrument right
乐器权利
so that's a mixed success or failure
所以这是一个混合的成功或失败
here's some pretty good one a group of
这里有 一些 非常好的一组
people on a on a field playing football
在踢足球的领域的人们
that's I would call that a you know a
那就是我会称之为你知道的
result maybe even A+ here's a group of
结果甚至A +这里是一组
people standing on top of a mountain
人站在高山 之巅
so less good there's a mountain but as
所以不太好，有一座山，但是
far as I can tell there's no people but
据我 所知，除此之外 没有 人
these systems like to see people because
这些系统喜欢看人
of both the combination because in the
这两个 组合因为 在
data set they were trained on there's a
他们接受过训练的数据集就是一个
lot of people and people often talk
很多人和人经常交谈
about people okay I mean and the fact
关于人们 好吧 我的意思和事实
that you can appreciate both what I said
你可以欣赏我说的话
and why it's funny that's there you did
为什么你做的很有趣
some of my cognitive activities that
我的一些认知活动
this system is not even trying to do
这个系统甚至都没有尝试
okay here we've got a building with the
好吧，我们这里 有一座建筑物
cake I'll go through these fast building
蛋糕我会经过这些快速 建筑
with the cake a large stone building
与蛋糕一块大石头建筑
with the clock tower I think that's
与钟楼我认为那是
pretty good I'd give that like a b-plus
非常好，我会像 b-plus 那样给予它
there's no clock but it's plausibly
没有时钟，但这似乎是合情合理的
right there might be a clock in there
那里可能有一个时钟
there's definitely something like that
肯定有类似的东西
here's a truck parked on the side of a
这是一辆停在一边的卡车
building I don't know maybe a b-minus
建筑我不知道可能是一个B-minus
there there is a car on the side of a
那边 有一辆车
building but it's not a truck and it's
建筑， 但它不是卡车，它是
and it's it's not doesn't seem like the
和它的岂不 似乎 不是 这样的
main thing in the image okay
图中的主要内容 还可以
here's a necklace made of bananas here's
这是一条由香蕉制成的项链
a large ship in the water this is pretty
水中的一艘大船很漂亮
good I give this like an a-minus or
好吧，我给这个像a-minus或者
b-plus because there is a ship in the
b-plus因为有一艘船在
water but it's not very large it's
水，但它不是很大
really more of like a tugboat or
真的更像 是一艘拖船或者
something here's a sign sitting on the
这里的东西是坐在上面的标志
grass you know in some sense that's
从某种意义上 说 你知道的草
great no but it but in another sense
伟大的不 ，但在另一种意义上
it's really missing what's actually
它真的错过了实际上的东西
interesting and important and meaningful
有趣，重要且有意义
to humans
对人类
here's a
这是一个
here's a garden is in the dirt a pizza
这是一个花园里的泥土比萨饼
sitting on top of the building a small
坐在楼顶 小
house with the red brick building that's
房子的红砖建筑 ，是
pretty good although a kind of weird way
相当不错， 虽然 是 一种 奇怪的方式
of saying it a vintage photo of a pond
的说 这 池塘里的复古照片
that's good they like vintage photos a
他们喜欢老式照片 ，这很好
group of people that are standing in the
那是 站在一群人
grass near a bridge again there's two
在桥附近的草再次有两个
people and there's some grass and
人们 还有一些草 和 草
there's a bridge but it's really not
有一座桥， 但事实并非如此
what's going on a person in the yard
这是怎么回事就 一个人在院子里
okay kind of a group of people standing
好吧一群 人站着
on top of the boat there's a boat
在 船的 顶部 有一条船
there's a group of people they're
他们是一群人
standing but again it's what the
站着，但又是什么了
sentence that you see is is more based
你看到的句子更基础
on a bias of what people have said in
关于人们 所说 的偏见
the past about images that are only
关于过去只有的图像
vaguely like this a clock tower is a
模糊地像这样一座钟楼 就是一座 钟楼
little at night that's really I think
我觉得，这真的很少
pretty impressive a large clock mounted
相当令人印象深刻的大钟安装
to the side of the building a little bit
到建筑物的一侧一 点点
less so a snow-covered feel very good a
不那么雪覆盖的感觉非常好了
building with snow on the ground a
建筑与地面上的雪a
little bit less good there's no snow
有点不太好，没有下雪
white some people who I don't know them
白人 我不 认识 他们
but I bet that's probably right because
但我敢打赌，这可能是对的，因为
face identifying faces and recognizing
面对识别面孔和识别
people who are famous because they won
因为 赢了而闻名的人
you know medals and the Olympics
你知道奖牌和奥运会
probably I would trust current pattern
可能我会相信目前的模式
recognition systems to get that a
识别系统得到一个
painting of a base in front of a mirror
在镜子前画一个底座
less good also a famous person there but
好少也是一个有名的人有 ，但
we didn't get him a person walking in
我们没有让他一个人走进 来
the rain again there is sort of a person
再次下雨有点像一个人
and there's some puddles but not you
而且有一些水坑，但不是你
know a group of stuffed animals a car
知道一群毛绒动物一辆车
parked in a parking lot that's good a
停在一个 很好的 停车场
car parked in front of a building less
车停在一幢建筑物前面
good a plate with a fork and knife a
用叉子和刀子好的盘子a
clear blue sky okay so you get the idea
清澈的蓝天好，所以你明白 了
again like if you actually go and play
再次就像你真的去玩
with the system partly because I think
与 系统部分原因是因为我觉得
Mike but my friends at Microsoft told me
迈克，但我在微软的朋友告诉我
they've improved at some you know I this
他们已经改善了一些，你知道 我这个
is partly for entertainment values you
部分是为了娱乐价值你
know I chose what also would be the
知道我选择什么也将是
funnier example so I'm quite I want to
更有趣的例子，所以我很想要
be quite honest about it and these are
对此非常诚实，这些都是
I'm not trying to take away what our
我不是想把 我们的东西带走
impressive AI technologies but I think
令人印象深刻的AI技术但我认为
it's clear that there's a sense of
很清楚， 有一种感觉
understanding any one of these images
理解这些 图像中的 任何一个
that it's important to see that even
即使这样 看 也 很重要
when it seems to be correct right if it
当 它似乎是 ，如果它 正确 的权利
can make the kind of errors that it
可以做出那种错误的 ，它
makes that even when it seems to be
即使 它似乎是这样的
correct it's probably not doing what
纠正它可能没有 做什么
you're doing and it's probably not even
你这样做，它可能不是 连
trying to scale towards the dimensions
试图扩大规模
of intelligence that we think about when
我们在何时思考的情报
we're talking about human intelligence
我们谈论的是人类智慧
okay another way to put this I'm going
好的另一种 方式，我要去
to show you a really insightful blog
向您展示一个真正富有洞察力的博客
post from one of your other speakers so
从你的 其他一位发言者那里发帖
in a couple of days I'm not sure you're
在几天之内，我 不确定 你是不是
going to have Andre
会有安德烈
Karpov a who's one of the leading people
卡尔波夫是谁的领导人之一
in deep learning this is a really great
在深度学习中， 这 真的很棒
blog post he wrote a couple of years ago
他 几年前 写 的 博客文章
when he was I think still at Stanford he
当 他我觉得还是在斯坦福大学，他
got his PhD from Stanford he did he
他从斯坦福大学获得博士学位
worked at Google a little bit on some
有些人在谷歌工作过一点点
early big neural net AI projects there
那里早期的大神经网络AI项目
he was an open AI he was one of the
他是一个开放的AI，他的一个
founders of open AI and recently he
开放AI的创始人和最近他
joined Tesla as their director of AI
加入特斯拉担任人工智能总监
research but about five years ago he was
研究，但大约五年前他是
looking at the state of computer vision
看着 计算机视觉的状态
from a human intelligence point of view
从人类智能的角度来看
and and lamenting how far away we were
并且哀叹我们离我们有多远
okay so this is the title of his blog
好的，所以这是他博客的标题
post the state of computer vision
发布计算机视觉状态
nai-nai we are really really far away
奈奈， 我们真的 很远
and he took this image which was a sort
他拍了这张 照片
of a famous image in its own right it
一个着名的形象 本身就是它
was a popular image of Obama back when
是奥巴马 当时流行的形象
he was president kind of playing around
他总统有点玩耍
as he liked to do when he was on tour so
因为他喜欢做的时候 ，他 就这么游
if you take a look at this you can see
如果你在这个看看 ，你 可以看到
you probably all can recognize the
你可能都认识到了
previous President of the United States
美国前任总统
but you can also get the sense of where
但你也可以了解到哪里
he is and what's going on and you might
他是，你发生了什么事，你可能会
see people smiling and you might get the
看到人们微笑，你可能会得到
sense that he's playing a joke on
感觉他正在玩笑话
someone can you see that right so how do
有人能看到你 这么做了吗？
you know that he's playing a joke and
你知道他在玩笑话
what that joke is well as Andre goes on
安德烈继续说这个笑话是多么的好
to talk about in his blog post too if
如果 在他的 博客文章中谈论
you think about all the things that that
你想想所有的事情， 那
you have to really deploy in your mind
你必须 真正部署在你的脑海里
to understand that it's a huge list of
要明白，这是一个巨大的列表
course it starts with seeing people and
当然，它始于看到人和
objects and maybe doing some face
对象，也许做一些面子
recognition but you have to do things
承认，但你必须做的事情
like for example notice his foot on the
例如像 注意到他的脚
scale and understand enough about how
规模和了解如何
scales work that when a foot presses
当脚按下时，秤可以工作
down it exerts force that the scale is
向下发挥规模所带来的力量
sensitive doesn't just magically measure
敏感不只是神奇地 测量
people's weight but it does that somehow
人们的体重，但不知何故
through force you have to see who can
通过力，你必须看到谁 可以
see that he's doing that and who can't
看到他正在做那个 ，谁做不到
who cannot see that he's doing that
谁也看不到他在做那件事
right in particularly the person on the
对，尤其是那个人
scale and why some people can see that
规模以及为什么有些人可以看到这一点
he's doing that and can see that some
他 这样做， 可以看到一些
other people can't see it why that makes
其他人无法看到 它 为什么做
it funny to them okay and someday we
这对他们来说很好笑， 总有一天我们
should have machines that can understand
应该有可以理解的机器
this but hopefully you can see why what
这但希望你 能 明白 为什么
I would I what the kind of architecture
我会是什么样 的 架构
that I'm talking about would be the
我正在谈论的 将是
building blocks of the ingredients to be
成分的 构建 块
able to get them to do that now I when I
能够 让他们 在我 做的 时候 做到这一点
again I prepared a version of this talk
我再次准备了这个演讲的一个版本
a few months ago and I wrote to Andre
几个月前， 我写信给安德烈
and I said I was gonna use this and I
而且我说我 会用这个而且 我
was curious if he how what you know if
如果他知道你是怎么知道的，他很好奇
he had any reflections on this and where
他对这个以及在哪里有任何反思
he thought we were relative to five
他以为我们相对于五岁
years ago because a certain
多年前因为一定的
a lot of progress has been made but he
很多已经取得了进展 ，但 他
said here's his email I hope he doesn't
说这是他的电子邮件， 我希望他没有
mind me sharing it but I mean again he's
请记住我分享它，但我的意思是他
a very honest person and that's one of
一个很老实的人 ，这是一个
the many reasons why he's such an
他之所以如此，原因很多
important person right now in AI okay
现在在AI的重要人物 好吧
he's both very technically strong and
他都非常技术上强大和
honest about what we can do what we
诚实是 我们可以做我们
can't do and as he says well what does
不能做， 因为他说得好
he say it's nice to hear from you it's
他说很高兴收到你 的消息
funny you should bring this up I was
有趣的是你应该提起我的意思
also thinking about writing a a return
还在考虑写一篇回报
to this and in short basically I don't
对此，简而言之，基本上我没有
believe we've made very much progress
相信我们已经取得了很大的进步
right he points out that in his long
他指出，在他的长期
list of things that you'd need to
你需要的东西清单
understand the image we have made
了解我们的形象
progress on some the ability to again
一些能力再次进步
detect people and do face recognition
发现人并进行人脸识别
for well-known individuals okay but
为知名人士不错 ，但
that's kind of about it all right
这是一种关于这 一切的权利
and he wasn't particularly optimistic
他并不是特别 乐观
that the current route that's being
那个正在的当前路线
pursued an industry is is anywhere close
追求一个行业是 近在咫尺
to solving or even really trying to
解决甚至真正 尝试
solve these larger questions um if we
如果我们解决这些更大的问题
give this image to that caption bot you
把这个图像给 你 那个 标题机器人
know what we see is again represents the
知道我们所看到的再次代表着
same point so here's the caption bot it
同一点，所以这里是标题机器人它
says I think it's a group of people
说我认为 这是一群 人
standing next to a man in a suit and tie
站在西装和领带 旁边的 男人
right so that's right right as far as it
右 所以这对对尽可能
goes it just doesn't go far enough and
它 走得还 不够 远
the current the current ideas of built a
当前 的内置了 当前的想法
data set train a deep learning algorithm
数据集训练深度学习算法
on it and then repeat um aren't really
在它上然后重复嗯不是真的
even I would venture trying to get to
即使我冒险试图去
what we're talking about or here's
我们在说什么或在这里
another I'll just give you one other
另一个 我只会给你 一个
example of a couple of photographs from
例如 ，从 一对夫妇的 照片
my recent vacation and a nice warm
我最近的假期 和温暖的
tropical look how which I think
热带看看我怎么想
illustrates ways in which again the gap
说明了再次出现差距的方式
where we have machines that can say beat
我们有机器可以说击败
the world's best at go but can't even
世界上最好的，但不能
beat a child at tick-tack-toe
在打勾的时候击败了一个孩子
now what do I mean by that well you know
那么你知道我的意思是什么？
of course we can build we don't even
当然我们可以建立我们甚至没有
need reinforcement learning or deep
需要强化学习或深入
learning to build a machine that can
学习建立 一台 可以 的机器
they can win or tie do is do optimally
他们可以获胜或领带做是最佳的
in tic-tac-toe but think about this this
在tic-tac-toe， 但想想 这个
is a real tic-tac-toe game which I saw
我看到的是一个真正的井字游戏
on the grass outside my hotel right what
在我酒店外面的草地上什么的
do you have to do to look at this and
你需要做什么才能看到这个和
recognize that it's a tic-tac-toe game
认识到这是一个 井字游戏
you have to see the objects you have to
你必须看到 你必须拥有 的对象
see what's you know in some sense
从某种意义上看你知道什么
there's a three by three grid but it's
有一个三乘三的网格，但它是
but it's only abstract right it's only
但它只是抽象的权利它是唯一的
delimited by this these ropes or strings
本 这些绳索或字符串分隔
okay it's not actually a grid in any
好吧， 它实际上并不是一个网格
simple geometric sense all right but yet
简单的几何感觉还可以
a child can look at that and indeed
一个孩子可以看到 这一点，的确如此
here's an actual child who was looking
这是一个正在寻找的真正的孩子
at it and recognized oh it's a game of
在它，并认识到 哦，这是一个游戏
tic-tac-toe and even know what they need
tic-tac-toe 甚至知道他们 需要 什么
to do to win
要做到 胜利
we put the X and completed and now
我们把X和现在完成了
they've got three in a row right that's
他们已经连续三次了
that's literally child's play okay
这真的是孩子的游戏好吧
you showed this sort of thing though to
你展示了这种东西
one of these you know image
其中一个你知道的形象
understanding caption BOTS and I think
理解标题BOTS，我想
it's a close-up of a sign okay again
这是一个标志的特写 再好
it's not like saying that this is a
这不是说这是一个
close-up of a sign is is not the same
标志的特写是不 一样的
thing I would venture as a as a
我冒昧 作为 一个事
cognitive or computational activity
认知或计算活动
that's going to give us what we need to
那将会给 我们什么 ， 我们需要
say recognize the objects to recognize
说识别要识别的对象
it as a game to understand the goal and
它作为一个游戏来理解目标和
how to plan to achieve those goals
如何计划实现这些目标
whereas this kind of architecture is
而这种 架构是
designed to try to do all of these
旨在尝试做所有 这些
things ultimately right and I bring in
事情最终是正确的，我带来了
these examples of games or jokes to
游戏或笑话这些例子
really show where perception goes to
真实地展示了感知的去向
cognition you know that and all the way
认识你知道，并一路
up to symbols right so to get objects
最多符号，以获得对象
and forces and mental states that's the
和力和心理状态是这样的
cognitive core but to be able to get
认知核心，但能够 得到
goals and plans and what do I do or how
目标和计划，我该怎么做或如何做
do I talk about it that's symbols okay
我谈论 它没关系符号
here's another way into this and it's
这是另一种方式，它是
one that also motivates I think a lot of
一个也激励我的想法很多
really good work on the engineering side
在工程方面 做得非常好
and a lot of our interest in the science
我们对科学很感兴趣
side is think about robotics and think
一边思考机器人 和思考
about what do you have to do to you know
关于你要做什么对你知道
what is the brain have to be light to
什么是大脑必须是光
control the body so again you're gonna
控制身体，所以你会再次
hear from shortly I think maybe it's
很快就听到我想也许就是这样
next week from Mark raybert who's one of
下周 马克雷伯特是其中之一
the founders of Boston Dynamics which is
波士顿动力公司的创始人是
one of my favorite companies anywhere
我最喜欢的公司之一
they're without doubt the leading maker
他们毫无疑问是领先的制造商
of humanoid robots legged locomoting
人形机器人腿部运动
robots in industry they have all sorts
在 工业中的机器人他们有各种各样的
of other really cool robots robots like
其他 很酷 的 机器人的机器人像
dogs robots that have all you know I
狗狗机器人，你知道我
think you'll even get to see a live
认为你甚至可以看到现场直播
demonstration of my new robots this
这个 我的 新机器人的 演示
really awesome impressive stuff okay um
非常令人印象深刻的东西好吧 嗯
but what about the minds and brains of
但是那些 思想和大脑呢？
these robots well again if you ask mark
如果你问马克，这些机器人又好了
ask them how much of human-like
问他们有多少像人一样
cognition do they have in their robots
他们在机器人中有认知吗？
and I think he would say very little in
我认为他会说 很少
fact we have asked him that and he would
事实上我们已经问过他了，他会的
say very little he has said very little
很少说他说的很少
he's actually one of the advisors of our
他实际上是 我们 的 顾问之一
Center and I think in many ways were
中心， 我认为在很多方面 都
very much on the same page we both want
非常多 ，我们都希望在同一页 上
to know how do you build the kind of
要 知道你是如何 构建的那种
intelligence that can control these
智能 ， 可以控制这些
bodies like the way a human does alright
身体就像人类 做得好的方式
um here's another example of an industry
这是另一个行业的例子
robotics effort this is Google's arm
机器人技术努力这是谷歌的手臂
farm
农场
where you know they've they've got lots
在那里你知道他们已经 有很多
of robot arms and they're trying to
机器人手臂，他们正在试图
train them to pick up objects using
训练他们使用
various kinds of deep learning and
各种深度学习和
reinforcement learning techniques and I
强化学习技巧 和我
think it's one approach I just think
认为这是我 想到的一种方法
it's very very different from the way
它与方式非常不同
humans learn to say control their body
人类学会说控制自己的身体
and manipulate objects and you can see
并操纵对象，你可以看到
that in terms of things that go back to
在那个回去物联网方面
what you were saying when you're
你说的 是什么
introducing me right think about how
介绍我正确思考 如何
quickly we learn things right here you
我们很快就会在这里学到东西
have these the arm farm is trying to
有这些手臂农场正在努力
generate you know effectively maybe if
如果你有效地生成你有效的知识
not infinite but hundreds of thousands
不是无限的，但几 十万
millions of examples of reaches and
数百万的达到和达到的例子
pickups of objects even with just a
物品的拾取， 即使只是 一个
single gripper and yet a child who in
单个抓手， 还有一个孩子
some ways can't control their body
有些方法无法控制自己的身体
nearly as well as robots can be
几乎与机器人可
controlled at the low level and is able
控制在低水平 并且能够
to do so much more so I'll show you two
做得 更多 所以我会告诉你两个
of my favorite videos from YouTube here
我最喜欢的视频来自YouTube
which motivate some of the research that
这激发了一些研究
we're doing the one on the left is a one
我们 左边的那个是 一个
and a half year old and the other ones a
和一个半岁，其他的一个
one year old so just watch this one and
一 岁，所以只看这个和
a half year old here doing a popular
一个半岁的人在这里做一个受欢迎的
activity for many kids as a playing hmm
许多孩子的活动作为一个游戏嗯
you see video up there I'd okay there we
你看到那里的视频 我在 那里我们没事
go okay so he's he's on doing this
好吧，所以 他就是这样做的
stacking Cup activity alright he's
堆叠杯活动 好吧，他是
stacking up cups to make a tall tower
堆叠杯子，使高塔
he's got a stack of three and what you
他有一堆三 和你
can see for the first part of this video
可以看到 这个视频 的 第一部分
is it looks like he's trying to make a
看起来他正试图 做一个
second stack and that he's trying to
第二堆， 他正在 努力
pick up at once basically he's trying to
马上接受 基本上他正在努力
make a stack of two that'll go on the
制作一堆 两个就可以了
stack of three and you know he's trying
一堆三 ，你知道他正在努力
to debug his plan because it's it got a
调试他的计划，因为它有一个
little bit stuck here but and think
有点卡在这里，但想想
about I mean again if you know anything
如果你知道的 话我的意思是 什么
about robots manipulating objects even
关于机器人甚至操纵物体
just what he just did no robot can
正是他刚刚做的没有机器人能做到的
decide to do that and actually do it
决定这样做并实际做到这一点
right at some point he's almost got it
在某些时候 他几乎 得到了 它
it's a little bit tricky but at some
这有点棘手，但在某些方面
point he's gonna get that stack of two
他会得到那 两个 筹码
he realizes he has to move that object
他意识到他已经来移动物体
out of the way look at what he just did
看看 他刚刚做 了 什么
move it out of the way use two hands to
把它移开， 用两只手来
pick it up and now he's got a stack of
把它捡起来，现在他有一个堆栈
two on a stack of three and suddenly you
两个在一堆三个突然你
know subgoal completed he's now got a
知道subgoal完成他现在有 一个
stack of five and he gives himself a
一堆五，他给自己一个
hand because he know he knows he
因为他知道他知道他
accomplished a keyway point along the
沿着这条路完成了一个关键点
way to his final goal that's a kind of
他的最终目标 是一种方式
early symbolic cognition right to
早期的象征认知权
understand that I'm trying to build a
明白我正在努力 建立一个
tall tower but a tower is made up of
高塔但塔是 由 塔 组成的
little towers it's you know it can end
小塔，你知道它 可以结束
and you can take a tower and put it on
你可以拿一座塔穿上它
top of another tower or stack a stack on
另一座塔的 顶部 或堆叠的堆栈
us
我们
a can you have a bigger stack right so
一，你可以有一个更大的堆栈 权利，使
think about how he goes from bottom up
想想他是如何自下而上的
perception to the objects of the physics
对物理对象的感知
needed to manipulate the objects to the
操作 对象的需要
ability to make even those early kinds
能够做出那些早期的那种
of symbolic plans at some point he keeps
在某些方面，他保持着象征性的计划
doing this he puts another stack on
他这样做了另外一堆
there I'll just jump to the end
我会 跳到 最后
oops sorry you missed it so he he gets
哎呀抱歉，你错过了， 所以他 得到了
really excited and he gives himself
真的很兴奋，他给自己
another big hand but falls over okay
另一个大手但是摔倒好了
again Boston Dynamics now has robots
波士顿动力公司现在拥​​有机器人
that could pick themselves up after that
在那之后可能会发现自己
that's really impressive again but all
这真是令人印象深刻 ，但所有
the other stuff to get to that point we
其他东西要达到 这一点我们
don't really know how to do in a robotic
真的不知道怎么做机器人
setting or think about this baby here
设置或 值得 思考 这件宝贝
this is a younger baby this is one of
这是一个年幼的宝宝，这是其中之一
the Internet's very most popular videos
互联网上 最受欢迎的 视频
because it features a baby and a cat and
因为它拥有一个孩子，一只猫和
but the babies doing something
但是婴儿在 做某事
interesting he's got the same cups but
有趣的是他有相同的杯子但是
he's decided he's again decided to try a
他决定再次决定 尝试一个
new thing so this think about creativity
新事物，所以这就考虑 创造力
he's decided that his goal is to stack
他 决定他的目标是 筹码
up cups on the back of a cat I guess
我想，在猫背上的杯子
he's asking how many cups can I fit on
他问我有多少的杯子可以装 上
the back of a cat well three let's see
一只猫的后面三个让我们看看
can I fit more let's try another one
我可以适应更多让我们尝试另一个
okay well he can't fit more than three
好吧，他不能 超过三个
it turns out and then he then does it's
事实证明，然后他就做了
not working so he changes his goal now
没有工作所以 他现在改变了他的目标
his goal appears to be to get the cups
他的目标似乎是得到 杯
on the other side of the cat now watch
现在看猫的另一边
that part when he reaches back behind
当他回到后面的那一部分
him there that's I'll just pause it
他在那里，我会暂停它
there for a moment
那一刻
umm someone he just reached back there
嗯，他 刚回到那里的人
that's a particularly striking moment in
这是一个特别引人注目的时刻
the video it shows a very strong form of
它显示了一个非常强大的视频形式
what we call in cognitive science object
我们称之为 认知 科学的对象
permanence okay that's the idea that you
永久性好的 ，这就是你的想法
represent objects as these permanent
将对象表示为永久性的
enduring entities in the world even when
即使在世界上，也是世界上持久的实体
you can't see them in this case he
你不能在这种情况下看到他们
hadn't seen or touched that object
没有看到或碰过那个物体
behind him for like at least a minute
跟在他身后至少一分钟
right maybe much longer I don't know and
可能更长，我 不 知道和
yet he still knew it was there and he
但他仍然知道它在那里和 他
was able to incorporate it in his plan
能够 将其纳入他的计划中
right there's a moment before that when
就在那之前的那一刻
he's about to reach for it but then he
他即将到来，但后来他
sees this other one right and it's only
看到另一个正确，这是唯一的
when he's now exhausted all the other
当他现在已经筋疲力尽了
objects here that he can see he's like
在这里，他可以看到他的样子
okay now time to get this object and
好的，现在是时候得到这个对象了
bring it into play right so think about
使其 发挥正确的左右思量
what has to be going on in his brain for
他脑子里 要发生什么
him to be able to do that right that's
他能够做到这一点 正确 的是
like the analog of you understanding
像 你理解 模拟
what's behind you okay um it's not that
什么在你身后好吧 ，不是这样的
these things are impossible to capture
这些 东西是不可能捕获的
machines far from it it's just that like
机器远离它就像那样
training a deep neural network or any
训练深层神经网络 或任何
kind of pattern recognition system we
我们的模式识别系统
don't think is going to do it but we
不要以为 我们会这样做
think by reverse engineering how it
通过逆向工程思考它是怎么回事
works in the brain
适用于大脑
we might be able to do it I think we can
我们也许可以做到这一点
can do it okay it's not just humans that
能做到这一点 好吧 ，不仅仅是人类
do this kind of activity here's a couple
在这里做这种 活动 的是一对
of again rather famous videos you can
你可以再次相当着名的视频
watch all of these on YouTube
在YouTube上观看所有这些内容
crows are famous object manipulators and
乌鸦是着名的物体操纵者和
tool users but also orangutangs other
工具用户，还有orangutangs等
primates rodents we can watch if we just
灵长类啮齿动物 我们可以看，如果我们只是
hey let me pause this one for a second
嘿，让我暂停一下这一秒
if we watch this orangutan here he's got
如果我们在这里观看这只猩猩，他就有了
a bunch of big legos and over the course
一堆大的 legos 和整个过程
of this video he's building up a stack
这段 视频 他正在建立 一个堆栈
legos it's really quite impressive
它真的令人印象深刻
you're just jumping to the end there's
你只是跳跃 到年底 有
actually some controversy out there of
实际上一些争议那里的
whether this video is a fake but the
这个视频是假的， 但是
controversy isn't about you know it's
争议不是 关于你知道的
not like whether it was I don't know
不喜欢是不是 我不知道
dumb with computer animation some people
有些人 用电脑动画愚蠢
think the video was actually filmed
认为视频实际上是拍摄的
backwards that a human built up the
向后，人类建立了
stack and the orangutan just slowly
堆栈和猩猩只是慢慢地
disassembled it piece by piece and it
它一块一块地拆开它
turns out it's remarkably hard to tell
事实证明这很难说
whether it's played forward or backwards
无论是前进还是后退
in time and people have argued over
在时间和人争论 过
little details because you know it would
细节，因为你知道它会
be quite impressive if an orangutan
如果是猩猩，那真是令人印象深刻
actually was able to build up this
实际上是能够建立这个
really impressive stack of Legos but I
真是令人印象深刻的一堆乐高积木但是 我
would submit that it would be almost as
会 提出它几乎 就是这样
impressive if he disassembled it think
令人印象深刻， 如果他拆卸它想
about the activity I mean if I wanted to
关于我的意思，如果我愿意的话
disassemble that the easiest thing to do
拆卸最简单的事情
would just be to knock it over
只是将它击倒
that's really all most robots could do
这真的是大多数机器人都可以做到的
but to piece by piece disassemble it
但 要一块一块地 拆开它
even if it's played backwards like this
即使它像这样倒退
that's still a really impressive act of
这仍然是一个非常 令人印象深刻的行为
symbolic planning on physical objects or
物理对象的符号规划
here you've got this this famous Mouse
在这里你有这个着名的鼠标
this you can find on the internet under
你可以在互联网上找到
the mouse versus cracker video and what
鼠标与饼干视频和什么
you'll see here over the course of this
你会看到这里在 这个 过程 中
video is a mouse valiantly and mostly
视频是一个勇敢 而且大多数 的鼠标
hopelessly struggling with a cracker
无可救药地与饼干挣扎
that they're hoping to bring back to
他们希望带回来
their nest I guess it's a very appealing
我认为这是一个非常有吸引力的巢
big meal and at some point after just
大餐 和 刚刚过后的某个时刻
trying to get it over the over the wall
试图把它翻过墙
at some point the mouse just gives up
在某些时候，鼠标就放弃了
because it's just never gonna happen and
因为它只是永远不会发生 ，
he just goes away except that because
除了那之外，他只是消失了
even Mouse's can dream or mice can dream
甚至老鼠都可以做梦，老鼠也可以做梦
some point he decides okay I'm just
有一点他决定好我只是
gonna come out for one more try and he
会出来的一个 尝试 和他
tries one more time and this time
再试一次这次
valiantly gets it over yeah isn't that
勇敢地得到它是的不是那样的
very impressive congratulations guys
非常令人印象深刻的祝贺
okay you don't have to clap form you can
好吧，你没有拍手形式你可以
clap for me at the end or clap for
为我鼓掌年底或鼓掌
whoever later okay but I want to applaud
谁后来没事，但我想鼓掌
the mouse there every time I see that
每当 我看到 它 时，鼠标就在那里
okay but again think what had to be
不错 ，但 再 想想什么都得是
going on in his brain
继续 他的 大脑
able to do that all right it's a crazy
能够做到这一点 没事 这是一个疯狂的
thing and yet he formulated the goal and
事情， 但他制定了目标和
was able to achieve it I'll just show
能够实现它 我只会 表现出来
one more video that is really more about
多一个视频是真的 更多
science these other ones are you know
科学这些其他的你知道吗？
some of them actually were from
他们中的一些实际上是从
scientific experiments but this is one
科学实验， 但这是一个
that motivates a lot of the science that
这激发了许多科学
I do and it's to me it sets up kind of a
我这样做，而且对我来说它设置了一种类型
grand cognitive science challenge for AI
人工智能的大认知科学挑战
and robotics it's from an experiment
和机器人技术它来自一个实验
with humans again eighteen month olds or
与人类再次十八个月大或
one-and-a-half year old so the the kids
一岁半 的孩子们
in this experiment were the same age is
在这个实验中，年龄相同
the first baby I showed you the one who
第一个孩子， 我告诉你那个人
did the stacking and 18 months is really
堆叠和18 个月 真的
a very very good age to study if you're
如果你是一个非常好的学习年龄
interested in intelligence for reasons
对情报感兴趣的原因
we can talk about later if you're
如果 你愿意，我们可以稍后讨论
interested this is from a very famous
感兴趣的是这是一个非常有名的
experiment done by two psychologists
由两位心理学家完成的实验
Felix Warren akin and Michael Tomasello
Felix Warren akin和Michael Tomasello
and it was studying the spontaneous
它正在研究自发的
helping behavior of young children it
帮助幼儿的行为 吧
also contrasted humans and chimps and
还对比人类和黑猩猩和
the punchline is that chips sometimes do
有利的是 芯片 有时会这样做
things that are kind of like what this
有点 像这样的东西
human did but not nearly as reliably or
人类做了但不是那么可靠或
as flexibly okay so not nearly it is and
灵活地好，所以几乎 不是
I'll show you a particular kind of
我会告诉你一种特殊的
unusual situation where human kids had
人类孩子们所处的异常情况
relatively little trouble figuring out
搞清楚相对来说很麻烦
kind of what to do or even whether they
什么 做 什么， 甚至 是他们
should do it whereas basically no chimp
应该这样做， 而基本上没有黑猩猩
did what you're gonna see humans
做了你会看到的人类
sometimes doing here so the experimenter
有时在这里做实验者
in this movie I'll turn on the sound
在这部电影中，我会打开声音
here if you can hear it the experimenter
在这里，如果你能听到实验者的话
is the tall guy and the participant is
是高个子，参与者是
the little kid in the corner there there
那边 角落里的小孩子
there's sound but no words right and at
有声音，但没有 正确的 话语
some point he stops and then the kid
有一点他停下来，然后是孩子
just does whatever they want to do so
只是做任何他们想这样做
watch what he does he goes over he opens
看着他 做了 什么 ， 他打开了
the cabinet looks inside then he steps
内阁看起来然后他走了
back and he looks up at felix and then
回来，他抬头看着 费利克斯 然后
looks down okay and then the action is
低头看好， 然后行动就是
completed now well wonder I want you to
完成 现在 很 奇怪我想要你
watch it one more time and think about
再看一遍并 思考
what's gotta be going inside the kid's
什么必须进入孩子的内心
head to understand this to understand
要明白这一点才能理解
like so it seems like what it looks like
像这样似乎它看起来像
to us is the kid figured out that this
给我们的是孩子想通了 这个
guy needed help and helped him and the
男人需要帮助，帮助他和他
paper is full of many other situations
纸上充满了许多其他情况
like this this is just one OK but the
像这样这 只是一个 好但是
key idea is that the situation is
关键的想法是， 情况是
somewhat novel people have seen people
有点新奇的人见过人
holding books and opening cabinets but
拿着书，打开 橱柜但是
probably it's very rare to see this kind
或许这是非常难得看到这种
of situation exactly right it's
情况 完全正确的是
different in some important details from
不同的一些重要细节来自
what you might have seen before and
你以前可能会看到的 和
there's other ones in there that are
那里还有其他的
really truly novel because they just
真的很新颖， 因为他们只是
made up a machine right there
在 那里 组成了一台机器
okay but somehow he has to understand
好吧但不知怎的，他必须明白
causally from the way the guy's banging
因为这个 家伙的敲打 方式因果关系
the books against the thing that it's
反对它的东西的书
it's sort it's sort of both a symbol but
它有点像 符号但是
it's also somehow he's got to understand
这也是他必须明白的
what he can do and what he can't do and
他能做些什么，什么 他不能 做，
then what the kid can do to help and
然后孩子可以做些什么来帮助和
I'll show this again but really just
我会再次展示这一点，但真的只是
watch the main part I want you to see is
观看我想让你看到的主要部分
I'll just sort of skip ahead so watch
我只想跳过去看看
this part here let's say I'll just jump
这部分让我们说我会跳
right when he watch right now he's about
就 在他 现在 看的时候，他 就是这样
to look up he looks up and makes eye
抬起头来抬起头来
contact and then his eyes look down so
接触 然后他的眼睛往下看
again he looks up he looks up and then a
他抬起头来 抬起头来然后看了一眼
saccade a sudden rapid eye movement down
扫视突然迅速的眼球运动下来
down to his hands up down okay so that's
直到他的手 向下 好，所以那就是
again that's this brain OS in action
再次， 这是大脑操作系统的行动
right he's making one glance small
他瞥了一眼
glance at the big guy's eyes just to
瞥了一眼这个大家伙的眼睛
make eye contact to see to get a signal
进行目光 接触以获得信号
did I understand what you wanted and did
我才明白你想要什么，做
you did you register that joint
你注册了那个 关节吗？
attention and then he makes a prediction
注意然后他做出预测
about what the guy's gonna do so he
关于那个人会怎么做他这样做
looks right down he doesn't just like
看起来他不喜欢
look around randomly he looks right down
随意地环顾四周， 他向下看
to the guy's hands to track the action
到那家伙的手上追踪 行动
that he expects to see happening if I
如果我 ，他希望 看到发生的事情
did the right thing to help you then I
我做了正确的事来帮助你
expect you're gonna put the books there
期待你将书放在那里
okay so you can see these things
好的，你可以看到 这些 东西
happening and we want to know what's
发生了， 我们想知道是什么
going on inside the mind that guides all
继续 引导所有人
of that all right so that's the sort of
那好吧 ，这样的排序
big scientific agenda that we're working
我们正在 努力的重大科学议程
on over the next few years where we
在接下来的几年里，我们在哪里
think some kind of human understanding
想一想人类的 理解
of human intelligence in scientific
科学的人类智能
terms could lead to all sorts of AI
术语可能导致 各种AI
payoffs in particular suppose we could
特别是 假设我们能够获得 回报
build a robot that could do what this
建立一个可以做到 这一点的机器人
kid and many other kids and these
孩子和许多其他孩子和这些
experiments do just say help you out
实验只是说帮助你
around the house without having to be
周围而 不必 房子
programmed or even really instructed
编程甚至真正指示
just to kind of get a sense oh yeah you
只是为了感觉 哦，是的，你
need to have at that shirt let me help
需要 有在 那件衬衣 让我帮
you out okay even 18 month olds will do
你 出去好吗甚至 18个月孩子会做
that sometimes not very reliably or
有时不太 可靠或
effectively sometimes they'll try to
有时他们会尝试
help and really do the opposite right
帮助， 真的做对了
but imagine if you could take the the
但想象一下，如果你能拿走
flexible understanding of humans actions
灵活理解 人类的行为
goals and so on and make those reliable
目标等等，使这些可靠
engineering technology that would be
工程技术将是
very useful and it would also be related
非常有用 ，也有关系
to say machines that you can actually
说机器，你可以实际
start to talk to and trust in some ways
开始 在某些方面 交谈 和信任
right that shared understanding so how
这是如何共享理解的权利
are we gonna do this well let me spend
我们要做好这件事让我度过难关
the rest of the time
剩下的时间
talking about how we try to do this
谈论我们如何尝试这样做
right some of the some of the technology
正确的 一些技术
that we're building both in our group
我们正在我们小组中建立
and more broadly to try to make these
并且更广泛地尝试制作这些
kinds of architectures real and I'll
各种 架构真实，我会
talk about two or three technical ideas
谈谈两三个技术思路
again not in any detail all right
再也没有任何细节了
um what is the idea of a probabilistic
嗯概率的概念是什么？
program so this is a kind of a you think
程序所以这是一种你认为的
of it as a computational abstraction
它作为计算抽象
that we can use to capture the
我们可以用来 捕获
common-sense knowledge of this core
这个核心 的常识性知识
cognition so when I say we have an
认知， 所以当我说我们有 一个
intuitive understanding of physical
直观地了解身体
objects in people's goals how do I build
人们的目标中的对象如何 构建
a model of that model you have in the
你所拥有 的 那种 模特的模型
head probabilistic programs a little bit
头概率程序一点点
more technically our one way to
从技术上讲， 我们的 唯一途径
understand them is as a generalization
理解它们是一种概括
of Bayesian networks or other kinds of
贝叶斯网络或其他 类型的
directed graphical models if you know
如果你知道，可以使用定向图形
those okay but where instead of defining
那些没关系，但 在哪里而不是 定义
a probability model on a graph you
图表上的 概率模型
define it on a program and thereby have
在程序上定义它，从而具有
access to a much more expressive toolkit
访问更具表现力的工具包
of knowledge representation so data
知识表示如此数据
structures other kinds of algorithmic
构造其他类型的算法
tools for representing knowledge okay
表示知识的工具还可以
but you still have access to the ability
但你仍然可以使用 这种能力
to do probabilistic inference like in a
像在a中那样进行概率推理
graphical model but also causal
图形模型也是 因果关系
inference in a directed graphical model
定向图形模型中的推理
so for those of you who know about
所以对于那些 了解的人
graphical models that might make some
图形模型可能会产生一些
sense to you but just more broadly what
对你有意义，但更广泛的是什么
this is think of this as as a toolkit
这被认为是一个工具包
that allows us to combine several of the
这使 我们能够把几个 的
best ideas not just of the recent deep
最好的想法不 只是最近的深
learning era but over if you look back
学习时代，但如果你回顾过去
over the whole scope of AI and as well
在整个AI的范围内也是如此
as cognitive science I think there's
作为认知科学， 我认为有
three or four ideas there and more but
那里有三四个想法，但更多
definitely like three ideas we could
绝对喜欢我们能做的三个想法
really put up there that have proven
真的在那里证明了
their worth and have have had have risen
他们的价值已经上涨了
and fallen in terms of each of these had
并且每个人都有所下降
ideas when the mainstream of the field
当 主流领域的想法
thought this was totally the way to go
认为这完全是要走的路
and every other idea was was obviously a
而其他任何想法显然都是 一个
waste of time and also had its time when
浪费时间，也有时间
many people thought it was a waste of
很多人认为 这 是浪费
time okay and these three big ideas I
时间 好， 这三个重要的 想法我
would say are first of all the idea of
会说是首先的 想法
symbolic representation or symbolic
象征性的表征或象征性的
languages for knowledge representation
知识表示语言
probabilistic inference in generative
生成中的 概率推理
models to capture uncertainty ambiguity
模型捕捉不确定性模糊
learning from sparse data and in their
从稀疏数据和他们的数据中学习
hierarchical setting learning to learn
分层设置学习学习
right and then of course the recent
对，然后当然是最近的
developments with neural inspired
神经启发的发展
architectures for pattern recognition
模式识别的体系结构
okay each of these things each of these
还好 每次的这些事情每一种
ideas symbolic languages
想法象征性语言
probabilistic inference and neural
概率推理和神经网络
networks has some distinctive strengths
网络有一些独特的优势
that are real weak points of the other
这 是 对方 真正的 弱点
approaches right so to take one example
接近，以举一个例子
but I haven't really talked about here
但我 在这里 没有真正谈过
people in the but I but you but you
人 在 ，但 我可是你，但 你
mentioned as an outstanding challenge
提到了一个突出的挑战
for neural networks transfer learning
用于神经网络转移学习
we're learning to take knowledge across
我们正在学习如何掌握知识
a number of previous tasks to transfer
一些 以前要转移的任务
to others this is a real challenge and
给别人，这是一个真正的挑战 ，
has always been a challenge in a neural
一直是 神经系统 的挑战
net ok but is something that's addressed
net ok 但是已经解决了
very naturally and very scalable in for
很自然的， 并非常可扩展
example a hierarchical Bayesian model
例如，分层贝叶斯模型
and if you look at some of the recent
如果你看一下 最近的 一些
attempts really interesting attempts
尝试真正有趣的尝试
within the deep learning world to try to
在深度学习世界中尝试
get kinds of transfer learning and
获得各种转学和 学习
learning to learn they're really cool ok
学习学习他们真的很酷
but many of them are in some ways kind
但其中许多在某种程度上是善良的
of reinventing within a neural network
在神经网络中重塑
paradigm ideas that people you know
你 知道 人 的思想范式
maybe just 10 or 15 years ago developed
可能只是 10或 15 年前开发的
in very sophisticated ways in let's say
我们以非常 复杂的方式说
hierarchical Bayesian models ok and a
分层贝叶斯模型确定和a
lot of attempts to get sort of symbolic
很多尝试 得到一种象征性的
algorithm like behavior in neural
神经网络中的行为算法
networks again are really you know
网络再次 真的你 知道
they're very small steps towards
他们 迈出了 非常 小的一步
something which is a very mature
一些非常成熟的东西
technology in computer systems and
计算机系统和技术
programming languages probabilistic
编程语言概率
programs I'll just sort of advertise
程序我只是 做广告
mostly are a way to combine the
大多数是一种结合的方式
strengths of all of these approaches to
所有这些方法的优势
have knowledge representations which are
有知识表示
as expressive as anything that anybody
像任何人一样富有表现力
ever did in the symbolic paradigm that
曾经在象征范式中做过
are as flexible at dealing with
在处理方面同样灵活
uncertainty and sparse data as anything
任何 不确定性和 稀疏数据
in the probabilistic paradigm but that
在概率范式中但是 那样
also can support pattern recognition
也可以支持模式识别
tools to be able to for example to do
例如可以做的工具
very fast efficient inference in very
非常快速有效的推理
complex scenarios and there's a number
复杂的场景，还有一些
of probably that's that that's the kind
可能那就是 那种
of conceptual framework there's a number
概念框架有一个数字
of actually implemented tools I'm point
实际上实现的工具我指出
two here on the slide a number of
这里有两个 幻灯片上的一些
probablistic programming languages which
可能的编程语言
you can go explore
你可以去探索
for example there's one that was
例如，有一个 是
developed in our group a few years ago
几年前 在 我们小组中发展起来的
almost 10 years ago now called church
差不多10 年前， 现在叫教堂
which was the antecedent of some of
这是某些人的先行者
these other languages built on a
这些其他语言建立在
functional programming course a church
功能性编程课程教堂
is a probablistic programming language
是一种可能的编程语言
built on the lambda calculus or really
建立在lambda演算或真的
in Lisp basically but there are many
在Lisp中基本上有很多
other more modern tools especially if
其他更现代的工具尤其如果
you are interested in neural networks
你对神经网络很感兴趣
there are tools like for example pyro or
有一些工具 ，比如pyro或
prob torch or Bayes flow that try to
尝试的 火炬或 贝叶斯流
combine all these ideas in a or for
结合所有这些想法 在 一个或
example Jen here which is a project of
示例Jen这里是一个项目
the Koch men's singles probably the
科赫男子单打可能是
computing group these are all things
计算组这些都是 事物
which are
哪个是
just in the very beginning stages very
就在最开始的阶段
very alpha but you can find out more
非常阿尔法， 但你可以找到更多
about them online or by writing to their
关于他们在线或 写信给他们
creators and I think this is a this is a
创作者，我认为这是一个
very exciting place where the
非常令人兴奋的地方
convergence of a number of different AI
收敛了许多 不同的AI
tools are happening and when and this
工具正在发生，什么时候和这个
will be absolutely necessary for making
制作绝对必要
the kind of architecture that I'm
我是 那种建筑
talking about work another key idea
谈论 工作的另一个重要理念
which we've been building on in our lab
我们在实验室里一直在建设
and I think again many people are using
而且我想 很多人 都在使用
some version of this idea but maybe a
这个想法的 某些版本， 但也许是一个
little bit different from the way we're
与我们的方式 有点 不同
doing it is what what version of this
这样做是 这个 什么 什么 版本
idea that I'd like to talk about is what
我想谈的 是什么
I call the game engine in the head so
我把头部称为游戏引擎
this is the idea that it's really what
这就是它真的是什么的想法
the programs are about when I talk about
这些节目是关于我谈论的
problems tick programs I haven't said
问题滴答程序我还没说
anything about what kind of programs
什么 样 的程序
we're using we're just basically these
我们正在使用我们基本上就是这些
probablistic programming languages at
可能的编程语言
their best and Church the language that
他们最好的和 教会的语言
that was developed by Noah Goodman and
这是 诺亚古德曼 开发的
Vikash and others and Dan Roy and our
Vikash和其他人 以及Dan Roy 和我们的
group some 10 years ago was intended to
组大约10 年前是为了
be a turing-complete probabilistic
是一个图灵完备的概率
programming language so any probability
编程语言所以任何概率
model that was computable or for whose
可计算的模型或其可用 的模型
inferences conditional inferences are
推论条件推论是
computable you could represent in these
你可以在这些中表示的可计算性
languages but that that leaves
语言， 但离开
completely open what what I'm actually
完全打开我实际上的东西
gonna what what kind of proto I'm gonna
我要去做什么样的原型
write to model the world and I've been
写给世界模型，我 去过
very inspired in the last few years by
在过去的几年中 通过非常鼓舞
thinking about the kinds of programs
考虑 各种节目
that are in modern video game engines so
这是现代视频游戏引擎所以
again I'm probably most of you are
我可能你们大多数人都是
familiar with these but if you're and
熟悉 这些，但 如果你和
increasingly they're playing a role in
越来越多他们正在玩的角色
all sorts of ways an AI but these are
人工智能的各种方式，但这些都是
tools that were developed by the video
由 视频 开发 的工具
game industry to allow a game designer
游戏产业允许游戏设计师
to make a new game with without having
使一个新的游戏，而 不必
to do most of in some sense many must
在某种意义上做 很多必须做的事情
have the hard technical work bison from
拥有艰苦的技术工作 野牛
scratch but rather to focus on the
划伤，而是 专注于
characters the world the story okay the
人物世界这个故事 好吧
things that are more interesting for
更有趣的事情
designing a novel game in particular we
特别是我们设计一款新颖的游戏
if we want a player to explore some so
如果我们希望玩家去探索 这样 一些
new three-dimensional world but to have
新 的三维世界，但有
them be able to interact with the world
他们能够 与世界互动
in real time and to render nice looking
实时 并呈现漂亮的外观
graphics in in real time in an
图形在实时中
interactive way as the player moves
玩家移动时的互动方式
around and explores the world or if you
环游世界或探索世界
want to populate the world with
要填充的世界
non-player characters that will behave
将扮演的非玩家角色
in a even vaguely intelligent way okay
以一种 甚至模糊的智能方式好吧
game engines give you tools for doing
游戏引擎给你的工具做
all of this without having to write all
所有这一切都无需 全部写下来
of graphics from scratch or all of
从头开始或全部 的 图形
physics the rules of physics from
物理学 物理学 的从规则
scratch so what are called game physics
所以所谓的游戏物理学
engines
引擎
and in some sense are a set of
在某种意义上说是一组
principles but also hacks from Newtonian
牛顿的原则也是黑客攻击
mechanics and other areas of physics
力学和其他物理领域
that allow you to simulate plausible
这 可以让你模拟合理的
looking physical interactions in very
非常看待身体上的互动
complex world very approximately but
复杂的世界非常近似但是
very fast there's also what's called
非常快，还有所谓的
game AI which are basically very simple
游戏AI基本上都很简单
planning models so let's say I want to
规划模型让我们说，我想
have an AI in the game that is like
在 游戏 中 有一个AI 就像
unguarded that gardens of base and a
无人看守的是碱和花园
player is gonna attack the space so back
玩家会 如此反击空间
in the old Atari days like when I was a
在 旧的Atari日子，就像我是一个
kid you know the guards would just be
小子， 你知道卫兵就是这样
like random things that would fire
喜欢随意 发射的 东西
missiles kind of randomly in random
导弹随机随机
directions at random times right but
在右随机时间的方向，但
let's say you want a guard to be a
让我们说你想要一个后卫成为一个
little intelligent so to actually look
小聪明所以要真正看
around him oh and I see the player and
在他周围 哦，我看到了球员和
then to actually start shooting at you
然后真正开始射击你
and to even maybe pursue you so that
并 甚至可能追求你，让
requires putting a little AI in the game
需要在 游戏中 加入一点AI
and you do that by having basically
而你基本上就是这样做的
simple agent models in the game so what
简单的代理模型在游戏中如此
we think and some of you might think
我们想，有些人可能会想
this is crazy and some of you might
这很疯狂，有些人可能
think this is very natural idea I get
我认为这是非常 自然的 想法
both kinds of reactions what we think is
我们 认为的两种反应
that these tools of you know past
你知道这些工具 过去了
approximate renderers physics engines
近似渲染器物理引擎
and sort of very simple kinds of AI
和一些非常简单的AI
planning are an interesting first
规划是一个有趣的 第一
approximation to the kinds of
近似于种类
common-sense knowledge representations
常识知识表示
that evolution has built into our brains
进化已经 融入 我们的 大脑
so when we talk about the cognitive core
所以，当我们谈论 认知核心
or how do babies start what's what you
或者婴儿如何开始 你的生活
know ways in which a baby's brain isn't
知道 婴儿的大脑不是的方式
a blank slate one interesting idea is
一块空白的石板，一个 有趣的想法 是
that it starts with something like these
它从 这样的东西 开始
tools and then wrapped inside a
工具，然后包裹在一个
framework for probabilistic inference
概率推理的框架
that's what we mean by promising
这就是我们的承诺
programs that can support many
可以支持许多人的程序
activities of common sense perception
常识感知活动
and thinking so I'll just give you one
我 想 我会给 你 一个
example what we call this intuitive
我们称之为直观的例子
physics engine okay so this is work that
物理引擎好，所以这是的工作 ，
we did in our groups that Pete Battaglia
我们在Pete Battaglia的团队中做过
and Jess Hamrick did started this work
而Jess Hamrick 确实开始了这项工作
about five years ago now
大约五年前的 现在
where we showed people you know in some
在那里我们展示了一些你认识的人
sense and this is this is also an
感觉，这也是一个
illustration of a kind of experiment
一种实验的插图
that you might do what you might keep
你可以做你可能会做的事
talking about science like I'll show you
谈论科学就像我会告诉 你的那样
now a couple of experiments right so we
现在我们做了几个实验
would show people simple physical scenes
会向人们展示简单的物理场景
like these blocks world scenes and ask
像这些阻挡世界的场景和问
them to make a number of judgments and
他们做出了 一些判断和判断
the model we built does it basically a
我们建造的模型 基本上 是一个
little bit of probabilistic inference in
一点点的概率推论
a game style physics engine it perceives
它所感知的游戏风格物理引擎
the physical state and imagines a few
身体状况和想象一些
different possible ways the world could
世界可以采用不同的方式
go over the next one or two seconds to
过了一 两 秒钟
answer questions like will the stack of
像堆栈一样回答问题
blocks fall
块 落
or if they fall how far will they fall
或者如果他们跌落了多远
or which way will they fall or what
或者它们将以何种方式落下或者是什么
would happen if say one of the colored
如果说其中一个有色的话就会发生
one color of blocks are one material
一种颜色的块是一种材料
like the green stuff is ten times
像绿色的东西是 十倍
heavier than the gray stuff or vice
比 灰色的东西还重
versa how will that change the direction
反之， 如何 改变 方向
of fall or look at those red and yellow
跌倒或看那些红色和黄色
stack blocks some of which look like
堆栈块 其中一些看起来像
they should be falling but aren't so why
他们应该会 下降，但并没有那么为什么
can you infer from the fact that they're
你能从他们的事实中推断出来吗？
not fall in that one color block is much
不是因为一个颜色 块很多
heavier than the other let me show you a
比其他更重的让我告诉你一个
sort of a slightly weird task it's in a
排序略有怪异的任务很的
behavioral experiment sometimes we we do
我们有时会做行为实验
weird things so that we can test ways in
奇怪的事情， 以便我们可以测试方式
which you use your knowledge that you
你使用你的知识
didn't just you know learn from pattern
不只是你知道从模式学习
recognition but use it to do new kinds
识别但用它 来做新 种
of tasks that you'd never seen before so
你以前从来没有见过 这样的任务
here's a task which you know many of you
这是你认识 很多人的 任务
have maybe seen me talk about these
也许已经看到了我谈论 这些
things so you might have seen this task
所以你可能已经看过这个任务
but probably only if you saw me give a
但可能只有你看到我给了一个
talk around here before we call this the
在我们称之为之前在这里谈谈
red yellow task and again we'll make
红黄色的任务，并再次我们会让
this one interactive so imagine that the
这个交互式所以可想而知，
blocks on the table are knocked hard
桌子上的积木被敲了敲
enough to bump the tables bumped hard
足以让桌子撞得很厉害
enough to knock some of the blocks onto
足以让一些块 到
the floor so you tell me is it more
所以你告诉我 它是更多
likely to be red blocks or yellow blocks
可能是红色块或黄色块
what do you say red okay good
你怎么说红好的好
how about here yellow good how about
这里的黄色怎么样怎么样
here uh-huh here here okay here here
这里嗯这里这里这里还好这里
okay so
可以，然后呢
you just experience for yourself what
你只是亲自体验一下
it's like to be an objective one of
它就像是一个客观的
these experience we just did the
我们刚刚做过这些经历
experiment here the data is all captured
在这里试验数据全部 被捕获
on video sort of right okay you could
视频类的权 没关系 你可以
see that sometimes people were very
看到有时人们非常
quick other times people were slower
其他 人很快就会变慢
sometimes there was a lot of consensus
有时会有 很多共识
sometimes there was a little bit less
有时会少 一点
consensus right
共识权利
that reflects uncertainty so again
这又反映了不确定性
there's a long history of studying this
研究 这个问题有很长的历史
scientifically that you know you could
科学地说你知道你可以
but you can see something you can see
但你可以看到你能看到的 东西
the probabilistic inference at work
工作中的概率推理
probabilistic inference over what well I
关于我的概率推断
would say one way to describe it is over
会说一种描述它的方法 已经结束了
one or a few short low precision
一个或几个短的 低精度
simulations of the physics of these
模拟这些物理学
scenes so here is what I mean by this
这样的场景在这里是什么意思呢
I'm gonna show you a video of a game
我要给 你看 一个游戏 视频
engine reconstruction of one of these
发动机重建其中之一
scenes that simulates a small bump so
模拟小凹凸的场景
here's a small bubble here's the same
这里有一个小泡泡也 一样
scene with a big bump okay now notice
现场有一个很大的凸起 现在 没事 通知
that at the micro level different things
在微观层面上 不同的东西
happen but at the cognitive or macro
发生但是在 认知或宏观上
level that matters for common sense
对 常识很重要的水平
reasoning the same thing happened namely
推理同样的事情就是这样
all the yellow blocks went over onto one
所有的黄色块都转到了 一块
side of the table and few or none of the
桌子的一边，很少或根本没有 的
red blocks did so it didn't matter reach
红色块做了所以它无关紧要
of those simulations you ran in your
你在那里运行的那些模拟
head you'd get the same answer in this
把头 你会得到 这个 相同的 答案
case right this is one that's very easy
案例权利这是一个非常容易的
and high confidence and quick also you
你也很 自信
didn't have to run the simulation for
没有运行模拟
very long you only have to run it for a
很长一段时间你只需要运行它
few time steps like that to see what's
这样的几个时间步骤，看看是什么
gonna happen or similarly here you only
会发生或类似的 只 在这里你
have to run it for a few time steps okay
有 几个时间步 没关系 运行
and it doesn't have to be even very
它不必 是 即使是很
accurate even a fair amount of
准确甚至 相当数量的
imprecision will give you basically the
不精确会给你 基本上 的
same answer at the level that matters
重要的相同答案
for common sense so that's the kind of
对于常识来说 就是那种
thing our model does it runs a few low
我们的模型做的事情是运行一些低
precision simulations for a few time
精确模拟一段时间
steps but if you take the average of
步骤，但如果你取平均值
what happens there and you compare that
那里发生了什么 ，你比较 一下
with people's judgments you get results
根据人们的判断，你会得到结果
like what I show you here the
就像我在这里向你展示的那样
scatterplot shows on the y-axis the
散点图 显示在 y轴上
average judgments of people on the
关于人的平均判断
x-axis the average judgments of this
x轴的平均判断
model and it does a pretty good job it's
建模和它做了不错的 工作， 这是
not perfect but the model basically
不完美但 基本上 是模型
captures people's graded sense of what's
捕捉人们对什么是分级感
going on in this scene and many of these
继续在这个场景和其中许多
others okay and it doesn't do it with
其他人还可以，而且不会这样做
any learning but I'll come back to that
任何学习，但我会回到 那
in a second it just does it by
在一秒钟内它只是做到了
probabilistic reasoning over a game
对游戏的概率推理
physics simulation now we can use and we
现在我们可以使用物理模拟和 我们
have used the same kind of technology to
使用了同样的 技术
capture in very simple forms really just
以非常简单的形式捕捉真的 只是
proofs of concept at this point the kind
在这一点上的概念证明的那种
of common-sense physical scene
常识性物理场景
understanding in child in a child
了解孩子的孩子
playing with blocks or other objects or
玩积木或其他物品或
in what might go on in a young child
在 一个年幼的孩子 可能会发生什么
understanding of other people's actions
了解其他人的行为
what we
我们是什么
called the intuitive psychology engine
称为直觉心理学引擎
where now the probabilistic programs are
现在在哪里概率程序
defined over these kind of very simple
这些非常简单的定义
planning and perception programs and I
计划和感知计划和我
won't go into any details I'll just
不会进入 任何细节，我就
point to a couple of papers that my
指向 我的几篇论文
group played a very small role in but we
除了我们，小组扮演了一个非常小的角色
provided some models which together with
提供了一些与之一起的模型
some infant researchers people working
一些婴儿研究人员工作
on both of these are experiments that
这两个都是实验
that were done with 10 or 12 month
这是在10或12个月完成的
infants so younger than even some of the
婴儿比一些人还要年轻
babies I showed you before but basically
我之前给你看过的宝宝， 但 基本上
like that youngest baby the one with the
就像那个最小的宝贝一样
cat here's an example of showing simple
这里的猫是一个简单的例子
physical scenes these are moving objects
物理场景这些是移动物体
to 12 month olds where they saw a few
到12个月大的他们看到了几个
objects bouncing around inside a gumball
物体在口香糖中弹跳
machine and after some point in time the
机器和一些 时间点 后
scene gets occluded you'll see the scene
场景被遮挡你会看到场景
is occluded and then after another
被封闭，然后是另一个
period of time one of the objects will
一段时间 的对象会
appear at the bottom and the question is
出现在底部，问题是
is that the object you expected to see
是 对象，你希望看到
or not is its expected or surprising the
或不 为 它的预期甚至令人惊讶
standard way you study what infants know
你研究婴儿知道的标准方法
is by is by what's called looking time
是什么叫做看时间
methods just like an adult if I show you
如果我告诉你， 就像成年人一样
something that's surprising you might
你可能会感到惊讶的 事情
look longer okay if you're bored you'll
如果你觉得无聊，那就再好吧
look away all right so you can do that
看远没事 ，所以你可以这样做
same kind of thing with infants and by
同样的事情与婴儿 和
measuring how long they look at a scene
测量他们 看场景的时间
you can measure whether you've shown
你可以衡量你是否已经表现出来
them something surprising or not all
他们令人惊讶 或不是 全部
right
对
people have there are literally hundreds
人们有数百人
of studies if not more using looking
研究如果不是更多使用外观
time measures to study what infants know
研究婴儿知道的时间措施
but only with this paper that we
但只有这篇论文，我们
published a few years ago did we have a
几年 前发表的我们有一个
quantitative model we're able to show a
定量模型我们能够 展示一个
relation between inverse probability in
反向概率的关系
this case and surprise so things which
这种情况和惊喜所以事情
were objectively lower probability under
下是客观概率较低
one of these probabilistic physics
这些概率物理学之一
simulations across a number of different
跨越许多不同的模拟
manipulations of how fast the objects
操纵物体的速度有多快
were where they were when the scene was
当场景来临的时候
occluded how long the delay was various
闭塞延迟多久各种
physically relevant variables how many
物理相关变量有多少
objects there were one type or another
物体有一种或另一种
infants expectations connected with this
婴儿期望与此相关
model or another paper that we published
模型或我们发表的另一篇论文
that one was was done that the
那是一个完成了
experiments that were done by era note
由 时代音符 都做过实验
eggless and Luca bananas lab here is a
这里的无蛋和卢卡香蕉实验室是一个
study that was done just recently by
研究刚完成的最近
sherry Lu inless spell keys lab at there
雪利酒 鲁inless法术按键实验室在 那里
at Harvard but they're part they're
在哈佛，但 他们是他们的一部分
partners with us and CBMM which was
与我们和CBMM合作
about infants understanding of goals so
关于婴儿对目标的了解如此
this is more like again understanding of
这更像是一次理解
agents and intuitive psychology
代理人和直觉心理学
we're in again in very simple cartoon
我们又在一个非常简单的卡通片中
scenes you show an infant an agent that
你向婴儿展示一个代理人的场景
seems to be doing something like an
似乎 做 了 类似的 事情
animated cartoon character but it jumps
动画卡通人物， 但它跳了起来
over a wall or
在墙上或
rolls up a hill or it jumps over a gap
卷起一座小山或它跳过一个空隙
and the question is basically how much
问题基本上 是多少
does the agent want the goal that it
代理人是否希望实现目标
seems to be trying to achieve and what
似乎是 想要实现什么
this study showed okay and the models
这项 研究表明没问题和模型
here we're done by Tomer omen was that
在这里，我们由 Tomer 预兆 完成了
infants appeared to be sensitive to the
婴儿似乎是敏感
physical work done by the agent the more
代理人完成的体力劳动越多
work the agent did in a sense of the
从某种意义上来说，代理人所做的工作
integral of force applied over a path
在路径上施加的力的积分
the more the infant's thought the agent
婴儿对代理人的思考越多
wanted the goal we think of this as
我们想要这个目标
representing what we've sometimes called
代表我们有时称之为的东西
the naive utility calculus so the idea
天真的效用计算所以这个想法
that there's a basic calculus of cost
有一个基本 的成本计算
and benefit you know we take actions
并且让你知道我们采取行动
which are a little bit costly to achieve
这是一个有点 昂贵的实现
goal states which give us some reward
目标状态给了我们 一些奖励
that's the most basic way the oldest way
这是最 古老的方式 最基本 的方式
to think about rational intentional
思考理性故意
action and it seems that even
行动， 似乎 连
ten-month-old
十月龄
understand some version of that where
明白 其中的一些版本
the cost can be measured in physical
成本可以用实际来衡量
terms
条款
okay I see I'm running a little bit
好吧， 我看到我跑了一点点
behind on time and and I wanted to leave
按时落后，我想离开
some time for discussion so I'll I'll
一段时间讨论， 所以我会
just go very quickly through a couple of
只是快速通过几个
other things and and Lee and happy to
其他的 事情和李和幸福
stay around at the end for discussion
留在最后讨论
okay
好的
the what I showed you here was the
我在这里给你看的是
science where does the engineering go so
科学工程在哪里 如此
one way one thing you can do with this
你可以用这种方式做一件事
is say build a machine system that can
是说建立一个可以的机器系统
look not a little animated cartoon like
看起来不像动画片那样
these baby experiments but a real person
这些宝贝实验但 真实的人
doing something and again combine
做某事 再次 结合起来
physical COFF and constraints of actions
物理COFF和行动约束
with some understanding of the agents
与 代理商 的一些理解
utilities that's the math of planning to
公用事业这是规划的数学来
figure out what they want it so look in
弄清楚他们 想要 什么， 所以看看
this scene here and see if you can judge
这个场景在这里，看看你能否判断
which object that the woman is reaching
哪个对象，这 名妇女在到达
for so you can see there's there's a
所以你可以看到那里有一个
grid of four by four objects there's
有 四个四个物体的网格
sixteen objects here and she's gonna be
这里有十六件物品，她 会的
reaching for one of them raise it's
到达其中一个 提高了 它
gonna play in slow motion but raise your
会以慢动作玩，但提高你的
hand when you know which one she's
当你知道她是哪一个时，请亲自动手
reaching for ok so just watch and raise
伸手可及，所以只需 观看并加注
your hand when you know which one she
当你知道她是谁时，你的手
wants okay so most of
想要好好这么多
they're up by now alright and notice I
他们现在 好起来注意我
was looking at your hands not here but
看着你的手不是在这里，而是
went but what happened is most of the
去了，但发生了什么是大部分
hands were up at the about the time when
大约在什么时候举手
that gray or the one that - line shot up
那灰色的或者 说 一个 -线冲高
okay
好的
that's not human data you provided the
那不是你提供的人类数据
data this is our model so our model is
数据这是我们的模型 所以我们的 模型是
predicting more or less when you're able
预测或多或少 ，当你能
to say what her goal was okay it's well
说她的目标是好的， 这很好
before she actually touched the object
在她真正碰到物体之前
how does the model work again I'll skip
该模型如何再次工作我将跳过
the details but it does the same kind of
细节， 但它做 同样 的
thing that that our models of those
我们的那些模型的东西
infants did namely it but in this case
婴儿就是这样，但在这种情况下
it does it with a full body model from
它是用一个全身模型来做的
robotics so we use what's called the mu
机器人技术所以我们使用 所谓 的 mu
Joko physics engine which is a standard
Joko物理引擎是 一个标准
tool in robotics for planning physically
用于物理规划的 机器人工具
efficient reaches of say a humanoid
人类的有效范围
robot and we say we can give this
机器人， 我们说我们可以给这个
planner program a goal object as input
计划程序将目标对象编程为输入
we can give it each of the possible goal
我们可以给每个可能的目标
objects as input and say plan the most
对象作为输入，并说计划最多
physically efficient action so the one
身体有效的行动所以一个
that uses like the least energy to get
使用最少的能量来 获得
to that object and then we can do a
到那个对象 然后我们 可以做一个
Bayesian inference this is the
贝叶斯推论就是这样
probabilistic inference part the program
概率推理部分是程序
is them is the MU Joker planner okay but
是他们是 MU 小丑策划师不错 ，但
then we can say I want to do Bayesian
然后我们可以说我想做 贝叶斯
inference to work backwards from what I
推断从我的工作倒退
observed which was the action to the
观察到哪个是动作
input to that program what goal was
输入该计划的 目标是什么
provided as input to the planner and
作为计划者的输入和
here you can see the full array of four
在这里你可以看到 四个 完整的数组
by four possible inputs and those bars
通过四个可能的输入和那些条
that are moving up and down that's the
被 上下 移动 是这样的
Bayesian posterior probability of how
贝叶斯后验概率如何
likely each of those was to be the goal
可能每个都是 目标
and what you can see is it converges on
并且你可以看到的是其收敛 于
the right answer at least well it turns
正确的答案 至少会好转
out to be the ground truth right answer
出于真实的正确答案
but it's also the right answer according
但它也是正确的答案
to what people think with about the same
对人们的 想法与此 相同
kind of data that people took now you
人们现在拿走的那种数据
might say well okay I'm sure if I just
可能会说好的 我确定我是否只是
wanted to build a system that could
想建立一个可以的系统
detect what somebody was reaching for I
发现有人为我找到了什么
could generate a training data set of
可以生成一个 训练数据集
this sort of scene and train something
这种场景和训练的东西
up to analyze patterns of motion but
达分析运动 的模式，但
again because the engine in your head
再次，因为你的头部 发动机
actually does something we think more
实际上我们做了更多的事情
like this it does what we call inverse
像这样它做我们所谓的逆
planning over a physics model it can
准备通过物理模型它可以
apply to much more interesting scenes
适用于更有趣的场景
that you haven't really seen much of
你还没有看到太多 的
before so take the scene on the left
在此之前拍摄左侧的场景
right where again you see somebody
你又看到某人了
reaching for one of a four by four array
达到四乘四阵中的一个
of objects but what you see is a strange
对象，但你看到的是一个奇怪的
kind of reach can you see why he's doing
你可以看到他为什么 这么做
that strange reach up there it's a
那奇怪的到达那里 是一个
little small but what is you can see
小的，但 你能看到什么
that he's reaching over something right
他正在克服正确的事情
it's actually a pane of glass right you
它实际上是一块玻璃窗对你而言
see that and then there's this other guy
看到那个，然后 是另一个人
who's helping him who sees what he wants
谁正在帮助那些看到自己想要的东西的人
and hands
和手
the thing he wants so how does the firt
他想要的东西是怎么样的
the guy in the foreground see the other
前景中的那个人看到了 另一个
guy's goal
男人的目标
how does he and for his goal and know
他如何以及他的目标和知识
how to help him and then how do we look
如何帮助他，然后我们如何看待
at the two of them and figure out who's
在他们两个， 并弄清楚谁是谁
trying to help who or that in a scene
试图 帮助 场景中的 谁或 那个
like this one here that it's not
像这样的人， 这 不是
somebody trying to help somebody but
有人试图帮助某人 但是
rather the opposite
恰恰相反
okay so here's a model on the left of
好的，所以这是 左边 的 模型
how that might work right and we think
这怎么可能正常，我们 认为
this is the kind of model needed to
这是需要 的那种 模式
tackle this sort of challenge here right
在这里解决这种挑战 吧
basically it's a model it's a we take
基本上它是我们采取的模型
this model of planning sort of maximal
这种规划最大化的模型
expected utility planning which you can
您可以预期的公用事业规划
run backwards but then we recursively
向后跑，但我们递归
nest these models inside each other so
将这些 模型嵌在彼此内部
we say an agent is helping another agent
我们说代理正在帮助另一个代理人
if this agent is acting apparently to us
如果这个代理人明显地对我们采取行动
seems to be maximizing an expected
似乎是最大化 预期
utility that's a positive function of
实用程序是一个积极的功能
that agents expectation about another
代理人对另一个人的期望
agents expected utility and that's what
代理人期望效用，那是什么
it means to be a helper hindering is
它意味着 成为一个阻碍的帮手
sort of the opposite if one seems to be
如果一个人似乎是相反的
trying to lower somebody else's utility
试图降低别人的效用
okay and we've used these same kind of
好的 ，我们已经使用了这些相同的类型
models to also describe infants
模型 还描述婴儿
understanding of helping and hindering
理解帮助和阻碍
in a range of scenes I'll just say one
在一系列场景中，我只想说一个
last word about learning because
关于学习的最后一句话因为
everybody wants to know about learning
每个人都想知道的 学习
and and the the key thing here and it's
而且这里的关键是它
definitely part of any picture of AGI
绝对是 AGI 的任何图片的 一部分
but the thought I want to leave you on
但我想想过 要 离开你
is really about what learning is about
真的是关于学习的内容
ok I'll be just a few more slides and
好吧，我 只是 再拍 几张 幻灯片了
then I'll stop I promise none of the
然后我会停止，我保证不会
models I showed you so far really did
到目前为止，我向你展示的模特确实如此
any learning they certainly didn't do
任何学习他们当然没有做
any task specific learning ok we set up
我们设置的任何特定任务学习
a probable state program and then we let
一个可能的州 计划，然后我们让
it to inference now that's not to say
它现在 推断 ，不是 说
that we don't think people learn to do
我们 不认为人们学 着做
these things we do but the real learning
我们做的这些事情，但 真正的学习
goes on when you're much younger right
当你 年轻 得多 的时候， 你会继续
everything I showed you in basic form
我以基本形式向你展示的一切
even a one-year-old baby can do ok the
即使是 一岁左右的宝宝可以做 ok 了
basic learning goes on to support these
基础学习继续 支持 这些
kinds of abilities not that there isn't
各种能力，而不是没有
learning beyond one year but the basic
学习超过 一年但基本
way you learn to say solve these physics
你学会说解决这些物理的方式
problems is what goes on in your baton
问题是你的接力棒发生了什么
in the brain of a child between 0 and 12
在0到12岁之间的孩子 的大脑 中
months so this is just an example of
几个月所以这只是一个例子
some phenomena that come from the
一些现象来自于
literature on infant cognitive
关于婴儿认知的文献
development these are very rough
发展这些 非常粗糙
timelines you can take pictures of this
时间表你可以拍 这个
if you like this is always a popular
如果你喜欢这总是很受欢迎
slide because it really is quite
滑， 因为它真的很好
inspiring I think and I can give you
鼓舞人心，我想，我可以给你
lots of literature pointers but I'm
很多文学指针，但我
summarizing in very broad strokes with
总结非常广泛的
big error bars what we've learned in the
我们在学习中学到了很多错误
field of infant cognitive development
婴儿认知发展领域
about when and how kids seem to have to
关于孩子们何时以及如何必须 这样 做
at least come to certain understand
至少得到一定的理解
of basic aspects of physics so if you
物理学的基本方面，如果你
really want to study how people learn to
真想研究 人们 如何 学习
be intelligent a lot of what you have to
要聪明很多 你所拥有的
study are kids at this age you have to
学习 是你必须的这个年龄的孩子
study what's already in their brain at
研究他们脑中已有的东西
zero months and what they learn and how
零个月，他们学到了什么， 怎么做
they learn between four six eight ten
他们在四点六八点之间学习
twelve and so on and on up beyond that
十二年 等等 和 起来除此之外，
okay now well effectively what that
好吧，现在好好有效
amounts to we think is if what you're
等于我们认为你是什么
learning is something like a let's say
学习 就像让我们说的那样
an intuitive game physics engine to
一个直观的游戏物理引擎
capture these basic abilities then what
捕捉这些基本能力然后是什么
we need if we're gonna try to
如果我们要尝试，我们需要
reverse-engineer that is what we might
逆向工程，这是我们 可能的
think of as a program learning program
被认为是一个项目 学习计划
if your knowledge is in the form of a
如果你的知识是以a的形式
program then you have to have programs
程序然后你 必须有程序
that build other programs right this is
该生成其他程序 的权利 ，这是
what I was talking about the beginning
我刚开始谈论的是什么
about learning as building models of the
关于学习建设模型的问题
world or ultimately if you think what we
世界或最终如果你认为我们是什么
start off with is something like a game
从一开始就像游戏一样
engine that can play any game then what
什么引擎 可以玩任何游戏
you have to learn is the program of the
你必须要学习的是 程序
game that you're actually playing or the
你正在 玩的游戏或游戏
many different games that you might be
你可能会有很多不同的游戏
playing over your life so think of
打自己的生活这么认为 的
learning as like programming the game
学习像编程 游戏
engine in your head to fit with your
你脑子里的引擎适合你的
experience and and to fit with the
经验和正好与
possibilities that you seem like you can
你似乎 可以的可能性
take now this is what you could call the
现在就这你可以调用什么
hard problem of learning if you come to
如果你来学习难以学习的问题
learning from say neural networks or
从神经网络或神经网络中学习
other tools and machine learning right
其他工具和机器学习 权
so what makes machine makes most of
那么是什么让机器成为最重要的
machine learning go right now and
机器学习，现在走正确的和
certainly what makes neural network so
当然是什么使神经 网络如此
appealing is that you can set up a
吸引人的是你可以设置一个
basically a big function approximator
基本上是一个大函数逼近器
that can approximate many of the
这可以接近很多
functions you might want to do in a
你 可能想要做的功能
certain application or task but in a way
某种应用 或任务但在某种程度上
that's end-to-end differentiable and
这是端到端的可区分和
with a meaningful cost function so you
具有有意义的成本函数，所以你
can have one of these nice optimization
可以有这些不错的优化之一
landscapes you can compute the gradients
你可以计算渐变的风景
and basically just roll downhill until
基本上只是滚下山直到
you get to an optimal solution but if
你得到一个最佳的解决方案，但如果
you're talking about learning as
你在谈论学习
something like search in the space of
像搜索空间的东西
programs we don't know how to do
程序，我们不知道该怎么做
anything like that yet we don't know how
这样的事情 我们还不知道怎么做
to set this up as any kind of a nice
把它设置为任何一种好的
optimization problem with any notion of
任何概念的优化问题
smoothness or gradients okay rather what
平滑或渐变还可以
we need is a instead of learning as like
我们需要的是一个而不是像学习一样
rolling downhill effectively right a
有效地向下滚动a
process which just if you're willing to
只是你愿意的过程
wait long enough you know some you know
等了很久你就知道了
simple algorithm will take care of think
简单的算法将照顾思考
of what we call the idea of learning as
我们称之为学习的想法
programming there's a popular metaphor
编程那是一个流行的比喻
in cognitive development called the
在认知发展中 称为
child of scientists which emphasizes
强调的科学家的孩子
children as active theory builders and
儿童作为积极的理论建设者和
children's play as a kind of kind of
儿童作为一种类型的打法
casual experimentation but this is the
随便的实验， 但这是
algorithmic complement to that what we
算法补充我们的
could call the child as
可以称孩子为
or around MIT will say the child is
或麻省理工学院会说孩子是
hacker but the rest of the world if you
如果你，黑客，但世界其他地方
say child is hacker they think of
说孩子是他们想到的黑客
something someone who breaks into your
某人 闯入你的东西
email and steals your credit card
发送电子邮件并窃取您的信用卡
numbers we all know that hacking is you
数字，我们都知道 黑客是你
know making your code more awesome right
知道让你的代码更加精彩吧
if your knowledge is some kind of code
如果你的知识是某种代码
or legal library of programs then
或者是合法的程序库
learning is all the ways that a child
学习是 孩子的 一切方式
hacks on their code to make it more
破解他们的代码以使其更多
awesome that more awesome can mean more
太棒了，更棒的可能意味着更多
accurate but it can also mean faster
准确但它也意味着更快
more elegant more transportable to other
更优雅更易于运输 到其他
applications or their tasks more
应用程序或其任务更多
explainable to others maybe just more
其他人可以解释的可能更多
entertaining okay children do all of
有趣的好孩子做的全部
them have all of those goals and
他们拥有所有这些目标
learning and the activities by which
学习和 活动
they make their code more awesome also
他们使他们的代码更真棒还
correspond to many of the activities of
对应于许多活动
coding alright so think about all the
编码好吧所以想想所有的
ways on a day-to-day basis you might
你可能每天都在这样做
make your code more awesome
让您的代码 更加精彩
all right you might tune you might have
好吧，你可能会调整你可能有的
a big library of existing functions with
一个包含现有功能的大型库
some parameters that you can tune on a
你可以调整一些参数
data set that's basically what you do
数据集基本上就是你做的
with backprop or stochastic gradient
使用backprop或随机梯度
descent in training a deep learning
培养深度学习的后裔
system but think about all the ways in
系统，但想想 所有的方法
which you might actually modify the
您可能 实际修改了
underlying function so write new code or
底层函数所以写新代码或
take old code from some other thing and
从其他东西中取出旧代码
map it over here or make a whole new
将它映射到这里或制作一个全新的
library of code or refactor your code to
的代码库或重构你的代码
some other you know some other basis for
其他一些你知道的其他基础
that that will work more robustly and be
这将更有力地 工作 和
more extensible or transpiling or
更可扩展 或转换或
compiling right or even just commenting
正确编译甚至只是评论
your code or asking someone else for
您的代码或 要求别人 为
their code ok again these are all ways
他们的代码再次 确定 这些都是 方法
that we make our code more awesome and
我们使我们的代码 更加真棒和
children's learning has analogs all of
孩子们的学习都有 类似 的东西
these that we would want to understand
这些我们想要 了解
as an engineer from an algorithmic point
从算法角度看作为工程师
of view so in our group we've been
在我们小组中我们一直都是如此
working on on various early steps
在 各种早期步骤上工作
towards this and again we don't have
朝着这个， 我们再也没有
anything like program writing programs
程序编写程序
at the level of children's learning
在儿童的学习水平
algorithms but one example of something
算法，但 东西 一例
that we did in our group which you might
我们 在 你们团队中 做过的事情
not have thought of being about this but
没有考虑 过这个 但是
it's definitely the AI work we did that
这绝对是我们做的AI工作
got the most attention in the last
在最后得到了最多的关注
couple of years from our group we had
我们团队 的几年 了
this paper that was in science it was
本文认为在科学 这 是
actually on the cover of science sort of
实际上是在科学的封面上
just hit the market at the right time if
如果，只是在合适的时间打入市场
you like and it got about a hundred
你喜欢它，它有大约一百个
times more publicity than anything else
宣传 比其他任何事情都要多
I've ever done which is partly a
我曾经做过哪一部分是
testament to the really great work that
证明了真正伟大的工作
Brendan Lake who was the first author
布兰登湖是第一作者
did for his PhD here but much more so
在这里为他的博士学位做了但更重要的是
just about the hunger for AI systems at
几乎是 对人工智能系统 的 渴望
the time when we published this in 2015
我们在2015年发布这篇文章的时间
and we built a machine system that the
我们建立了一个机器系统
way we described it what
方式我们描述了什么
doing human level concept learning four
做人类水平的概念学习四
simple concept very simple visual
简单的概念非常简单的视觉
concepts these handwritten characters in
这些手写字符的概念
many of the world's alphabets for those
世界上许多字母对于 那些
of you who know the famous Emnes data
了解着名的Emnes 数据的人
set in the data set of handwritten
设置在手写的数据集中
digits 0 through 10 or 30 through 9
数字0到10或30到 9
sorry that drove so much good research
对不起，开了这么多好的研究
in deep learning and pattern recognition
深度学习和模式识别
it did that not because Jana Kuhn who
它做到了那不是 因为 Jana Kuhn的人
put that together or Geoff Hinton who
把那个放在一起或者Geoff Hinton是 谁
did a lot of work on deep learning with
做了很多工作 ， 对深 学习
M Nez they were interested fundamentally
M Nez他们从根本上感兴趣
in character recognition that they saw
在他们看到的字符识别中
that as a very simple testbed for
这是一个非常简单的测试平台
developing more general ideas and
发展更多的一般想法和
similarly we did this work on getting
同样地，我们做了这项工作
machines to do what we kind of one-shot
机器做我们 一次性的
learning of generative models also to
学习生成模型 也是 为了
develop more general ideas we saw this
我们看到了更多的一般想法
as learning very simple little mini
作为学习非常简单的小迷你
probabilistic programs in this case what
在 这种情况下 概率程序 是 什么
are those programs they're the programs
那些 节目是他们的 节目
you use to draw a character so ask
你用来绘制一个 角色所以问
yourself how can you look at any one of
自己，你怎么看待中的任何一个
these characters and see in a sense how
这些人物从某种意义上看是怎样的
somebody might draw it the way we tested
有人可能会按照我们测试的方式绘制它
this in our system was this little
在我们的系统中这是一点点
visual Turing test where we showed
我们展示的视觉图灵测试
people one character in a novel alphabet
人们在小说字母表中的一个字符
and we said draw another one and then we
我们说了另一个然后 我们
compared nine people like say on the
比较九个人喜欢说的
left and nine samples from our machine
从我们的 机器左侧和九个 样品
say on the right and we said we asked
在右边说，我们说我们问过
other people could you tell which was
其他人你能分辨出哪个是
the human drawing another example or
人类绘制另一个例子或
imagining another example in which was
想象中这是另一个例子
the machine and people couldn't tell
机器和人分不清楚
when I said ones on the left ones on the
当我说左边的那些
right I don't actually remember and on
对， 我 实际上并不记得和
different ones you can see if you can
如果可以，你可以看到不同的
tell it's very hard to tell can you tell
告诉你这很难说
which is for each one of these
这 对这些每一个
characters which new set of examples
新的一组 例子
were drawn by a human versus a machine
是由人类与机器绘制的
here's the right answer and probably you
这是正确的答案，也许你
couldn't tell the way we did this was by
无法分辨我们这样做 的 方式
assembling a simple kind of program
组装一个简单的程序
learning program right
学习计划权利
so we basically said when you draw a
所以我们基本上说当你画一个
character you're assembling strokes and
你正在组装笔画的角色
sub strokes with goals and sub goals
具有目标和子目标的子笔画
that produce ink on the page and when
在页面上产生墨水的时间
you see a character you're working
你看到你正在工作的角色
backwards to figure out what was the
向后找出是什么
program the most efficient program that
计划最有效的计划
did that so you're basically inverting a
这样做，所以你基本上反转了一个
probabilistic program doing Bayesian
做贝叶斯算法的概率程序
inference to the program most likely to
推断最有可能的计划
have generated what you saw this is one
已经产生了你看到的这是一个
small step we think towards being able
我们认为能够做到的一小步
to learn programs to being able to learn
学习计划，能够学会
something ultimately like a whole game
最终像整场比赛的东西
engine program the last thing I'll leave
引擎程序 我将离开 的 最后一件事
you with is just a pointer to sort of
你只是 排序的 指针
work in action
在 行动中工作
right so this is some work being done by
这是一些正在完成的工作
a current PhD student who works partly
现任博士生，部分工作
with me but also with armando salar
和我一起，还有阿曼多撒拉族
Lezama and cecil this is kevin Ellis
Lezama和 塞西尔这是凯文 埃利斯
it's an example of what's now I think
这是我现在想到的一个例子
again a
再来一次
urging exciting area and AI well beyond
敦促激动人心的地区和AI远远超出
anything that we're doing is the is
我们正在做的任何事情都是
combining techniques from where amando
结合阿曼多的技术
comes from which is the world of
来自哪个世界
programming languages not machine
编程语言不是机器
learning or AI but tools from
学习或人工智能，但工具来自
programming languages which can be used
可以使用的编程语言
to automatically synthesize code okay
自动合成代码好
with the machine learning toolkit in
使用机器学习工具包
this case a kind of Bayesian Men and a
这种情况是一种贝叶斯 男人和 一种
minimum description length idea to be
最小描述长度的想法
able to make again what is really one
能够 再次制作真正的东西
small step towards machines that can
迈向机器的小步骤
learn programs by basically trying to
通过基本尝试学习程序
efficiently find the shortest simplest
有效地找到 最简单的
program which can capture some data set
可以捕获一些数据集的程序
so we think by combining these kinds of
所以我们通过结合这些类型来思考
tools in this case let's say from
在这种情况下的工具让我们说
Bayesian inference over programs with a
用程序进行贝叶斯推理
number of tools that have been developed
已 开发的工具数量
in other areas of computer science that
在 计算机科学 等领域 是
don't look anything or haven't been
不 看任何东西或 没有 看过
considered to be machine learning or AI
被认为是机器学习或AI
like programming languages it's one of
就像编程语言一样
the many ways that going forward we're
我们前进的方式很多
gonna be able to build smarter more
要 能够建立更聪明
human-like machines so just to end then
人类机器就这样结束了
what I've tried to tell you here is
我试图 在 这里 告诉 你的是
taught first of all identify the ways in
首先 教会 识别方法
which human intelligence goes beyond
哪种人类智慧超越
pattern recognition to really all these
模式识别真的所有这些
activities of modeling the world okay to
建模世界的活动还可以
give you a sense of some of the domains
给你的一些领域 感
where we can start to study this in
在哪里我们可以开始研究这个
common sense scene understanding for
常识场景理解
example or you know something like
例如， 或者你知道类似的东西
one-shot learning for example like what
一次性学习，例如什么
we were just doing there or learning is
我们只是在那里做或学习
programming the engine in your head okay
你可以在头脑中编程引擎
and to give you a sense of some of the
并给你的一些感
technical tools probabilistic programs
技术工具概率计划
program synthesis game engines for
程序综合游戏引擎
example as well as a little bit of deep
例如以及 深一点点
learning that bringing together we're
学习把 我们 聚集在一起
starting to be able to make these things
开始能够制作这些东西
real okay now that's the science agenda
真的没关系，现在这是 科学 议程
and the reverse engineering agenda but
和逆向工程议程但是
think about for those of you who are
为 那些你的人思考
interested in technology what are the
感兴趣的技术 是 什么
many big AI frontiers that this opens up
这开放的 许多大的AI前沿
so the one I'm most excited about is
所以我最兴奋的 是
this idea which is which I've
这个想法就是我所做的
highlighted here in our big research
在我们的重大研究中突出显示
agenda this is one I'm most excited
议程这是我最 兴奋的一个
about to work on for the you know it
即将为你所知道的工作
could be the rest of my career honestly
可能是我职业生涯的其余部分
but it's really what is what is the
但它真的是什么
oldest and maybe the best dream of AI
最古老也许是人工智能的最佳梦想
researchers of how to build a human-like
研究人员如何建立一个像人类一样的人
intelligence system a real a GI system
智能系统是真正的地理标志系统
it's the idea that Turing proposed when
这是图灵提出的时候的想法
he proposed the Turing test or Marvin
他提出了图灵测试或马文
Minsky proposed this at different times
明斯基在不同时期提出了这个建议
in his life or many people have proposed
在他的生活中或许 多人提出过
this right which is to build a system
这是建立一个系统的权利
that grows into intelligence the way a
长在智力的一种方式
human does that starts like a baby and
人类就像 婴儿 一样开始
learns like a child
像孩子一样学习
tried to show you how we're starting to
试图告诉 你我们是如何开始的
be able to understand those things what
能够 理解那些 东西是什么
a baby's mind starts with how children
宝宝的思想从孩子的方式开始
actually learn and looking forward we
实际上学习 和期待 我们
might we might imagine that someday
我们可能会想象有一天
we'll be able to build machines that can
我们将 能够制造 机器， 可以
do this I think we can actually start
这样做我认为我们 实际上 可以 开始
working on this right now and we're and
这一权利的工作，现在，我们是和
that's something that we're doing in our
那是我们在做的事情
group so if that kind of thing excites
如果这种事情兴奋的话，那就小组吧
you then I encourage you to work on it
那么我鼓励你去做
maybe even with us or if any one of
也许甚至与我们或如果有任何一个
these other activities of human
这些人类的 其他活动
intelligence excite you I think taking
情报激动你我认为
the kind of science-based reverse
那种以科学为基础的逆转
engineering approach that we're doing
我们正在做的工程方法
and then trying to put that into
然后试着把它放进 去
engineering practice it's it's this is
工程实践就是这样
this is a this is not just a possible
这是一个 不仅仅是一种可能
route but I think it's it's quite
路线，但我认为这是相当的
possibly the most valuable route that
可能是最有价值的途径
you could work on right now to try to
你可以工作在现在尝试
actually achieve at least some kind of
实际上至少实现了某种
artificial general intelligence
强人工智能
especially the kind of intelligence AI
尤其是一种 智能 的 AI
system that's going to live in a human
将 要生活在人类中的系统
world and interact with human there's
世界与 人类互动
many kinds of AI systems that could live
可以存活的多种AI系统
in worlds of data that none of us can
在数据的世界是我们 没有 人能
understand or will ever live in
了解或将永远生活在
ourselves but if you want to build
我们自己， 但如果你想建立
machines that can live in our world and
可以生活在 我们这个世界的 机器
interact with us the way we are used to
与我们互动， 我们 习惯的 方式
interacting with other people then I
然后我 与其他 人互动
think this is a route that you should
认为这是你应该的路线
consider okay thank you
考虑好吧谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]
hi there so early in the talk you
你好， 那么早就说话了
expressed some skepticism about whether
对是否表示了一些怀疑
or not industry would get us to
或者不是工业会让我们接受
understanding human level intelligence
了解人类的智力
it seems that there's a couple of trends
似乎有 一些 趋势
that favor industry one is the industry
有利于行业的 是行业
is better than that academia
比那个学术界好
accumulating resources and plowing back
积累的资源和犁背
into the topic and it seems at the
进入主题，它似乎在
moment we've got a bit of brain drain
我们有一点 人才流失的那一刻
going on form academia into industry and
从学术界进入工业和
that seems like a on going trend yeah if
这似乎 是一个正在发展的趋势， 如果
you look at something like learning to
你看看学习的东西
fly or learning to fly into space then
飞或学习 飞上太空 ，然后
it looks like a story is one of Industry
它看起来像一个故事是工业之一
kind of taking over the field and going
有点接管领域 和去
off on its own yeah a little bit
关闭 自身耶一点点
academia academics still have a role but
学术界的学者仍然有作用 但是
industry kind of dominates so yes is
行业类型占主导地位，所以 是的
industry going to overtake the field you
行业将超越你的领域
think well that's a really good question
我认为这是一个非常好的 问题
and it's got several good questions
它有几个很好的问题
packed into one there right I didn't
在那里包装成一个 我没有
mean to say I didn't this wasn't meant
意思是说我没有这不是意思
to say go academia bad industry right
说去学术界做坏事吧
what I was taught what I what I tried to
我所教我的东西是什么我试着
say was the approaches that are
说的是方法
currently getting the most attention in
目前受到最多的关注
industry and they're really because
工业，他们真的是因为
they're really the most valuable ones
他们真的是最有价值的
right now for the short term you know
你知道，现在短期内
any industry is really focused on what
任何行业都真正专注于什么
it can do what are the value
它可以做什么是价值
propositions on basically a two year
提议基本上是两年
time scale at most I mean if you ask say
时间刻度最多我的意思是，如果你问的话
Google researchers to take the most
谷歌研究人员最多
prominent example it's pretty much what
突出的例子， 它几乎 是什么
they'll all tell you okay maybe maybe
他们都会告诉你好吧 也许吧
things that might you know pay off
你可能 知道的事情会 得到回报
initially in two years but maybe take
最初在两年但可能需要
five years or more to really develop but
五年或更长时间真正发展但是
if if you can't show that it's gonna do
如果你不能表明它会这样做
something practical for us in two years
两年内 对 我们来说很实用的东西
in a way that matters for our bottom
以一种对我们的底部至关重要的方式
line then it's not really worth doing
那么这不值得做
okay so what when we say what I'm
好的，那么当我们说出我的意思时
talking about is the technologies which
谈论的是技术
right now industry sees as meeting that
现在工业界认为会议就是这样
specification and what I'm saying is
规范和我所说的是
right now I think those that's that's
现在我认为那就是那个
not where the route is to something like
不是路线的地方
human-like but not the most valuable
人性化但不是最 有价值的
promising route to human-like kinds of
有希望的人类类型的路径
AI systems all right but I hope that
AI系统的所有 权利，但 我希望 ，
like in the cases you said you know the
比如你说你知道的情况
basic research that we're doing now will
我们现在正在 做的基础研究
be successful enough that it will get
足够成功， 它会得到
the attention of industry when the time
当时 的行业 关注
is right but I think so you know I mean
是对的，但我 想你知道我的意思
I hope at some point you know it won't
我希望在某些时候 你知道它不会
it will only at least the engineering
它至少只会是工程
side will have to be done in industry
必须在工业上完成
not just in academia but you're also
不 只是在学术界 ，你也是
pointing to issues of like brain drain
指着人才流失的问题
and other things like that
和其他类似的事情
but I think it's these are real issues
但我认为这些 都是真正的问题
confronting our community I think
我认为面对我们的社区
everybody knows this and I'm
大家都知道这一点，我
this will come up multiple times here
这将在这里出现多次
which is you know I think we have to
你知道我认为我们 必须这样做
find ways to even now to combine the
找到即使现在结合的方法
best of the idea of the energy and the
最好能和的想法
resources of academia and industry if we
如果我们 学术和 工业的 资源
want to keep doing basically something
我想继续做 一些 基本的 事情
interesting right if we will if we just
如果我们将有趣的权利，如果 我们只是
want to redefine AI to be well whatever
我想重新定义人工智能
people currently call AI but scaled up
人们目前打电话给人工智能，但规模扩大
well then then then fine forget about it
那好，然后 再 细 忘掉它
and or if we just want to say let me and
或者如果我们只是想说让我和
people like me do what we're doing at
我这样的人做我们 在 做什么
what industry would consider a snail's
什么行业会考虑蜗牛
pace on toy problems okay fine but if
玩具问题的速度还好，但如果
but if we want to if you know if I want
但如果我们想要，如果你知道我是否想要
to take what I'm doing to the level that
把我正在做的事情带到那个水平
that will really be you know paying off
那真的是你知道还清
that level the industry can appreciate
该行业 可以 欣赏的 水平
or just that really has technological
或者只是真的有技术
impact on a broad scale right or I think
对大范围的影响或我 认为
if industry wants to take what it's
如果工业想要采取它的东西
doing and really build machines that are
做和真正建立机器
actually intelligent right our machine
实际上智能对我们的机器
learning that actually learns like a
学习，实际上学习像一个
person then I think we need each other
那么我认为我们需要彼此
now and not just in some point in the
现在不只是在某些点
future so this is a general challenge
未来所以这是一个普遍的 挑战
for MIT and for everywhere and for
麻省理工学院，无处不在
Google I mean we just spent a few days
Google 我的意思是我们只花 了几天时间
talking to Google about exactly this
与 谷歌谈论 这件事
issue that this was a talk I prepared
问题是 这是我准备的一个话题
partly for that purpose so we wanted to
部分是为了这个目的 ， 所以 我们想
raise those issues and and it's just I
提出这些 问题，这只是我
mean really there I don't know what I
意思是真的在那里我不知道我是什么
mean well rather I can think of some
意思是我可以 想到 一些
solutions to that problem of what you
解决你的问题
could call brain drain from the academic
可能会引起 学术界的 人才流失
point of view or what you could call
观点 或你可以打电话
just narrowing in into certain local
只是缩小到某个地方
minima in the industry point of view but
minima在业界的观点但是
they will require the leadership of both
他们需要两者的领导
academic institutions like MIT and
麻省理工学院和麻省理工学院
companies like Google being creative
谷歌这样的公司很有创意
about how they might work together in
关于他们 如何 在一起工作
ways that are a little bit outside of
方法是外一点点
their comfort zone I hope that will
他们的舒适区我希望会这样
start to happen including at MIT and at
开始发生， 包括麻省理工学院和
many other universities and at companies
许多其他大学 和 公司
like Google and many others and I think
像谷歌和其他许多人一样 ，我认为
we need it to happen for the health of
我们需要 它来 实现健康
all parties concerned okay thank you
有关各方好的 谢谢
very much things I'm curious about sort
非常多 的事情， 我很好奇 排序
of the premise that you gave that one of
你给了那个人的前提
the big gaps missing at determining
在确定时缺少大的差距
intelligence is the fact that we need to
智力是 我们需要 这样 的事实 ：
teach machines how to recognize models
教机器如何识别模型
and I'm curious as to what you think
我很好奇你的想法
sort of non goal oriented cognitive
一种非 目标导向的认知
activity comes into play they're things
活动发挥作用他们是事情
like feelings and emotions
喜欢感情和情绪
and and y-you don't think that might not
和你 - 你不 认为那可能不会
necessarily be like that the no I'm I
一定是那样的 我不是我
was born in questo the only reason
出生于questo唯一的原因
emotions didn't appear on my slide is
情绪没有出现在我的幻灯片上
because there's a few reasons but the
因为 有几个原因但是
slide is only so big I wanted the font
幻灯片只有这么大 我 想要的字体
to be big readable for such an important
对于如此重要​​的人来说，这是一个很大
slide I've had versions of my slide in
滑动 我有我的幻灯片的版本
which I do talk about that okay it's not
这一点我谈论还好 这不是
that I think feelings or emotions aren't
我认为感情或情绪不是
important I think they are important and
重要的是我认为它们 很重要
I used to not have many insights on it
我 以前对它 没有 太多的见解
about what to do about them but actually
关于如何应对他们，但实际上
partly based on some of my colleagues
部分基于我的一些同事
here at MIT BCS Laura Schultz and
在麻省理工学院BCS Laura Schultz和
Rebecca Saxe two of my cognitive
丽贝卡萨克斯我认知的两个
colleagues in who I work closely with
我与之密切合作的同事
they've been starting to do research on
他们一直在研究
how people understand emotions both
人们如何理解情绪
their own and others and we've been
他们自己和他人，我们一直都是
starting to work with them on
开始 与他们合作
computational models so that's actually
计算模型实际上就是这样
something I'm actively interested in and
我真正 感兴趣的 东西
even working on but I would say and
甚至工作 ，但我会说和
again for those of you who study emotion
再研究那些研究情感的人
to know about this actually you're gonna
实际上你知道这件事
have Lisa coming in right oh so she's
让丽莎进来吧 哦，所以她是
gonna basically say a version of the
基本上会说一个版本的
same thing I think the deepest way to
同样的事情我认为 最深的方式
understand she's one of the world's
了解她是世界上的一个
experts on this the deepest way to
专家就此最深入的方式
understand emotion is very much based on
理解情绪是非常 基础
our mental models of ourselves of the
我们自己 的心理模型
situation we're in and of other people
我们在和其他人的情况
right think about for example all of the
正确地想想所有 的
different I mean if you you know if you
不同意思，如果你知道 你是不是
think about it I mean again Lisa will
想一想，我的意思是 丽莎会的 意思
talk all about this but if you think
谈谈这一切， 但如果你认为
about emotion as just a very small set
关于情感只是一个非常小的集合
of what are sometimes called basic
什么 有时 被称为基本
emotions like being happy or angry or
喜欢快乐或生气的情绪
sad or you know those are a small number
伤心或你知道那些是一个 小数字
of them right there's usually only few
他们通常只有 少数
right you might not say you might see
对， 你可能不会说你可能会看到
that it's somehow like very basic things
它有点像非常基本的 东西
that are opposed to some kind of
反对某种形式的
cognitive activity but think about all
认知活动，但想想 所有
the different words we have for emotion
我们对情感的不同用语
right for example think about an a
例如，考虑一个a
famous cognitive emotion like regret
着名的认知情绪就像遗憾
what does it mean to feel regret or
感到 遗憾或是 什么意思
frustration right just to know both for
沮丧只是为了了解两者
yourself when you're not just feeling
当你不仅仅是感觉时，你自己
kind of down or negative but you're
有点下降或负面，但你是
feeling regret that that means something
感到遗憾，那 意味着什么
like I have to feel like there's a
就像我必须 感觉 有一个
situation that came out differently from
出现的情况 不同于
how I hoped and I realize I could have
我多么希望，我意识到我可以拥有
done something differently right so that
做了不同的事情以便这样做
means you have to be able to understand
意味着你必须 能够理解
you have to have a model you have to be
你必须要有一个模特
able to do a kind of counterfactual
能够做一种反事实
reasoning and to think oh if only I had
推理并思考哦，如果我只有
acted to differ
行为不同
way then I can predict that the world
那么我可以预测世界
would have come out differently and
本来会有所不同
that's the situation I wanted but
那是我想要 的 情况 但是
instead it came up this other way right
相反，它出现了另一种方式
or think about frustration again that
或者 再次 考虑 挫败感
requires something like understanding
需要类似理解的东西
okay I've tried a bunch of times I
好吧，我已经尝试过 很多次了
thought this would work but it doesn't
认为这会 起作用， 但 事实并非如此
seem to be working maybe I'm ready to
似乎 工作也许我已经准备好了
give up though those are all those are
放弃，虽然这些都是那些
those are very important human emotions
那些是非常重要的人类情感
we have to understand to understand
我们必须明白才能理解
ourselves we need that to understand
我们自己需要了解这一点
other people to understand communication
其他人了解沟通
but those are all filtered through the
但这些都是通过过滤掉的
kinds of models of action that I was
我是 哪种 行动 模式
just the ones I was talking about here
就是我在这里谈论的那些
with these say cost-benefit analyses of
用这些说成本效益分析
action so what I'm so I'm just trying to
行动所以我只是想这样做
say I think this is very basic stuff
说我认为这是 非常 基本的东西
that will be the basis for building I
这将是建立我的基础
think better engineering style models of
想想更好的工程风格模型
the full spectrum of human emotion
全方位的人类情感
beyond just like well I'm feeling good
除此之外 ， 我 感觉良好
or bad or scared okay
或坏或害怕好
and if I think when you see Lisa she
如果我认为你看丽莎她
will in her own way say something very
她会以自己的方式说些什么
similar interesting thanks yeah thanks
类似的有趣的谢谢，谢谢
Josh for your nice talk so all is about
乔希，你的好话， 所以一切都是关于
human cognition and try to build a model
人类的认知，并试图建立一个模型
to mimic those cognition but you don't
模仿那些认知，但你没有
how much could help you to understand
多少可以帮助你理解
how the circuit implement those things
电路 如何 实现这些 功能
hmm I mean like these circuits in the
嗯，我的意思是像这些电路
brain yeah yeah that's the is that what
大脑是啊是啊那是什么
you work on by any chance is that what
你工作的任何机会都是什么
you work on by any chance yeah yeah yeah
你有机会继续工作是的，是的，是的
so so in the Center for brains minds of
所以在 大脑心灵 中心 也是如此
machines as well as in brain and
机器以及脑和脑
cognitive science yeah we I have a
认知科学是的，我有一个
number of colleagues who study the
研究的同事数量
actual hardware basis of this stuff in
这个东西的实际硬件基础
the brain and that includes like the
大脑，包括像
large-scale architecture of the brain
大规模的大脑架构
say like what Nancy kanwisher
说像南希kanwisher
Rebecca Saxe studied with functional
Rebecca Saxe 研究了功能性
brain imaging or the more detailed
脑成像或更详细
circuitry which usually requires
通常需要的电路
recording from say non-human brains
记录来自非人类的大脑
right at the level of individual neurons
在单个神经元的水平
and connections between neurons all
和 所有 的神经元之间的连接
right so I'm very interested in those
对， 所以我 对这些非常感兴趣
things although it's not mostly what I
事情，虽然它不是我的主要内容
work on right but I would say you know
正确的工作， 但我会说你知道
again liking in many other areas of
在许多 其他领域再次喜欢
science certainly in neuroscience the
科学肯定 在 神经科学中
kind of work I'm talking about here in a
我正在谈论的一种工作
sort of classic reductionist program
一种经典的还原计划
sets the target for what we might look
为我们的目标设定目标
for like if I if I just want to go I
因为如果我，如果我只是 想去我
mean I I would I would I would assert
意思是我会坚持
right or my working conjecture is that
对，或者我的工作猜想就是这样
if if you do the kind of work that I'm
如果你做的那种 工作 我是
talking about here it gives you the
在这里谈论它给 你
right targets or gives you a candidate
正确的目标或给你一个候选人
set of targets to look for what are the
目标设定为寻找哪些
neural circuits computing right whereas
神经电路计算正确而
if you just go in and just say
如果你只是进去然后说
poking around in the brain or have some
在大脑中四处寻找或有一些
idea that what you're gonna try to do is
想法， 要去尝试做 你 是什么
find the neural circuits which underlie
找到基础的神经回路
behavior without a sense of the
没有的意识行为
computations needed to produce those
产生这些的计算
behaviors I don't I think it's gonna be
行为我不 认为这会是
very difficult to eat to know what to
吃东西很难知道该怎么做
look for and to know when you've found
寻找并知道 你 何时 找到
even viable answers so I think that's
甚至可行的答案，所以我认为
you know that's the standard kind of
你知道这是 标准 的 那种
reductionist program but it's not that's
还原计划， 但不是那样的
it's not I also think it's it's not one
这不是我也认为它不是一个
that is I'm divorced from the study of
那就是我离开了研究
neural circuits it's also one if you
神经回路它也是一个如果你
look at the broad picture of reverse
看一下反向的广阔画面
engineering it's one where we're neural
设计 它是我们神经的地方
circuits and understanding the circuits
电路和理解电路
in the brain play an absolutely critical
在大脑中 发挥绝对关键
role okay I would say the mate as an
角色好吧我会说配偶是一个
when you look at the brain at the
当你看着大脑的时候
hardware level as an engineer I'm mostly
作为工程师的硬件水平我主要是
looking at the software level right but
正确看待软件 层面 但是
when you look at the hardware level
当你看到硬件级别
there are some remarkable properties one
有一些非凡的属性之一
remarkable property again is you know
你知道，再次出色的财产
how much parallelism there is and in
多少并行存在，并在
many ways how fast the computations are
计算速度有多快
okay
好的
neurons are slow but the computations
神经元很慢但计算量很大
intelligence are very fast so how do we
智力非常快， 所以我们如何
get elements that are in some sense
获得某种意义上的元素
quite slow in their time constant to
他们的时间常常很慢
produce such intelligent behavior so
产生这样的智能行为
quickly that's a great mystery and I
很快，这是一个很大的谜， 我
think if we understood that it would
想想如果我们明白它会
have payoff for building all sorts of
有建设 各种各样的 回报
you know Apple basically application
你知道Apple基本上是申请
embedded circuits okay but also maybe
嵌入式电路不错，但 也可能
most important is the power consumption
最重要的是功耗
and again many people have-have have
而且很多人 都有
noted this right if you look at the
如果你看一下就注意到这一点
power consumption the power that the
耗电量的功率
brain consumes like what did I eat today
大脑消耗就像我今天吃的东西一样
okay almost nothing um my daughter who's
好吧， 几乎没有什么是我女儿的
again she's doing an internship here she
再次，她在这里做实习，她
literally yesterday all she ate was a
从字面上看，昨天她吃的都是一个
burrito and yet she wrote 300 lines of
卷饼，但她写的300 行
code for her internship project on
她的实习 项目 代码
really cool computational linguistics
非常酷的计算语言学
projects so somehow she turned a burrito
项目所以不知怎的，她变成了卷饼
into you know a model of child language
你知道一种儿童语言模型
acquisition okay but how did she do that
收购还好，但她是怎么做到的
or how do any of us do this right um
或如何做任何我们这样做的权利 嗯
we're if you look at the power that we
如果你 看看 我们 的力量， 我们就是
consume when we simulate even a very
当我们模拟一个非常的时候消耗
very small chunk of cortex on our
我们的皮质非常小
conventional hardware or we do any kind
传统硬件或我们做任何种类
of machine learning thing we have
我们有机器学习的东西
systems which are very very very very
系统非常非常非常非常
far from the power of the human brain
远离人脑的力量
computationally but in terms of physical
计算上但在物理方面
energy consumed way way past what any
能量消耗的方式通过任何方式
individual brain is doing so how do we
个人大脑正在这样做我们怎么做
get circuitry of any sort biological or
获得 任何 生物或 电路
just any physical circuit
任何物理电路
to be as smart as we are with as little
和 我们一样聪明
energy as we are this is this is a huge
能源，因为我们 这是一个巨大的
problem for basically every area of
基本上每个 领域 的问题
engineering right if you want to if you
如果你愿意，可以选择工程师权利
want to have any kind of robot the power
想拥有任何一种机器人的力量
consumption is a key bottleneck same for
消费是 同样 的关键瓶颈
self-driving cars if we want to build AI
如果我们想要建立AI，那就是自动驾驶汽车
without contributing to global warming
没有助长全球变暖
and climate change let alone use AI to
和 气候变化 更不用说使用AI了
solve climate change we really need to
解决我们真正需要的气候变化问题
address these issues and the brain is a
解决这些 问题 和大脑是 一个
is a huge guide there right I think
我认为 这是一个巨大的指导
there are some people who are really
有些 人 真的
starting to think about this how can we
开始思考 这个 我们 怎么样
say for example build somehow brain
比如以某种方式构建大脑
inspired computers which are very very
灵感来自非常非常的计算机
low-power but maybe only approximate so
低功率但 可能只是近似的
I'm thinking here of Joe Bates I don't
我在想乔·贝茨我不知道
know if none of you know Joe he's he's
知道如果你们都不 认识乔，他就是他
been around MIT and other places for
一直在麻省理工学院和其他地方
quite a while can I tell them about your
我可以告诉他们 你的相关信息
company so so Joe has a start-up in
公司所以乔有一个初创公司
Kendall Square called singular computing
肯德尔广场称为奇异计算
and they have some very interesting
他们有一些非常 有趣的
ideas including some actual implemented
想法包括一些实际实施
technology for low power approximate
低功耗近似技术
computing in a sort of a brain like way
像某种大脑一样计算
that might lead to possibly even like
这可能导致甚至可能
the ability to build something this is
能够 建立这样的东西
Joe's dream to built in this about the
乔的梦想是建立在这个关于
size of this table but that has a
这个表的大小， 但有一个
billion course a billion cores and runs
十亿美元的核心 和运行 十亿
on a reasonable kind of power
在合理的力量
consumption I would love to have such a
消费我会 喜欢这样的
machine if anybody wants to help Joe
机器， 如果有人想帮助乔
build it I think he'd love to talk to
建立它我认为他喜欢 和他说话
you but that's it's one of a number of
你， 但这是众多的一个
ideas I mean Google X people are working
想法 我的意思是 谷歌X人正在
on similar things probably most of the
在类似的事情 可能大部分
major chip companies are also inspired
各大芯片公司也受到启发
by this idea and I think even if you
通过 这个想法，我想即使你
don't didn't think you were interested
不要以为你不感兴趣
in the brain if you want to build the
在大脑中，如果你想建立
kind of AI were talking about and run it
AI正在谈论并运行它
on physical Hardware of any sort and
在物理硬件上的任何种类和
understanding how the brain circuits
了解大脑如何回路
compute what they do what what I'm
计算他们做什么我是什么
talking about with as little power as
用尽可能少的力量来谈论
they do I don't know any better place to
他们我不知道更好的地方
look it seems like a lot of the
看起来好像很多
improvements in AI have been driven by
人工智能的改进受到了推动
increasing like computational power yeah
像计算能力一样增加是的
how far you would you say me like GPUs
你会在多大程度上说我像GPU一样
or CMU yeah yeah how far would you say
或CMU是的，你会说多远
we are from hardware that could run a
我们 来自 可以运行的 硬件
general artificial intelligence of the
一般人工智能
kind that I'm talking about yeah I don't
那种我说的 是的，我没有
know I'll start with a billion cores and
知道我会从十亿个核心开始
then we'll see I mean I I think we're I
然后我们会看到我的意思 是我 认为 我们就是我
think we're I mean I think I think
我想我们的意思是我想我 想
there's no way to answer that question
没有办法回答这个 问题
in a way that software independent I
以某种软件独立的方式我
don't know how to do that right but I
不知道该怎么做正确的，但 我
think that
认为
it's and and you know I don't know like
它是，你知道我不知道
when you say how far are we
当你说我们有多远
you mean how far am i with the resources
你的意思是我与资源有多远
I have right now how far am i if if
我现在有多远，如果是的话
Google decides to put all of its
谷歌决定全力以赴
resources at my disposal like they might
我可以随意使用的资源
if I were working at deepmind
如果我 在深度工作
I don't know the answer to that question
我不知道这个 问题 的答案
I but I think the I think what we can
我，但我认为我认为我们 能做到的
say is this um individual neurons I mean
说这是我个人神经元的意思
again this goes back to another reason
这又回到 了另一个 原因
to study neural circuits um if you look
如果你看 ，研究神经回路
at what we currently call neural
我们目前称之为神经
networks in the AI side the model of a
AI侧 的网络模型
neuron is this very very simple thing
神经元是非常 简单的事情
right individual neurons are not only
正确的个别神经元不仅仅是
much more complex but have a lot more
更复杂，但有更多
computational power it's not clear how
计算能力还不清楚如何
they use it or whether they use it but I
他们使用它或是否使用 它，但我
think it's just as likely that a neuron
认为它 与神经元 一样 可能
is something like a rail you write is
就像你 写 的铁轨一样
that a neuron is something like a
一个 神经元就像一个
computer like under one neuron in your
计算机就像下一个神经元 中的
brain is more like a CPU node okay maybe
大脑更像是一个CPU 节点 好吧
and thus the ten billion or trillion you
因而你就是一百亿或万亿
know the large number of neurons in your
知道你身上的大量神经元
brain I think it's like 10 billion
大脑我觉得它就像100亿
cortical pyramidal neurons or something
皮质锥体神经元或其他东西
might be like 10 billion cores okay for
可能会像10个十亿 内核 为 好
example that's at least as plausible I
这个例子至少 看似合情合理
think to me as any other estimate so and
我认为和其他任何估计一样
I think so I think we're on the
我想是的，我认为我们正在努力
definitely on the underside with very
绝对在底面非常
big error bars so I completely agree
大错误吧所以我完全同意
that or if this is what you might be
或者如果这 是你可能的
suggesting and may you know going back
建议，也许你知道回去
to my answer to your question I don't
我的 回答 你的问题我不知道
think we're gonna get to what I'm
我想我们会得到 我的意思
talking about that anything like a real
谈论像一个真正的任何东西
brain scale without major innovations on
没有重大创新的大脑规模
the hardware side and you know it's it's
硬件方面 ，你知道它就是它
interesting that what drove those
有趣的是，是什么推动了 那些
innovations in that support current a I
支持 当前的创新I
was mostly not AI it was the video game
大部分不是AI，这是电子游戏
industry I'm when I point to the video
当我指向视频时，我就是这个行业
game engine in your head that's a
你头脑 中的游戏引擎是一个
similar thing that was driven by the
类似的东西是由...驱动的
video game industry on the software side
软件 方面的视频游戏 产业
I think we should all play as many video
我想我们都应该播放尽可能多的视频
games as we can and contribute to the
我们可以为游戏做出贡献
growth of the video game industry
视频游戏 产业的增长
because no because I mean I mean you can
因为不，因为我的意思是我的意思是你可以
see this in very like there are
非常喜欢看到这个
companies out there for example there's
以 那里的公司为例
a company called improbable which is a
一个名为不可能的公司是其
London company London based startup a
伦敦公司 总部位于伦敦的 一个启动
pretty sizable start-up at this point
在这一点上相当大的初创公司
which is building something that they
正在构建 他们的 东西
call spatial OS which is it's a it's not
呼叫空间OS这是它的一个它 不
a it's not a hardware idea but it's a
这不是硬件理念，但它是一个
kind of software idea for very very big
一种非常 非常大 的软件理念
distributed computing environments to
分布式计算环境
run much much more complex realistic
运行起来要复杂得多
simulations of the world for
为世界模拟世界
much more interesting immersive
更有趣的身临其境
permanent videogames I think that's one
永久的电子游戏我认为这是一个
thing that might hopefully that will
可能会有希望的东西
lead to more fun new kinds of games but
导致 更多有趣的新游戏，但
that's one example of where we might
这是我们可能的一个例子
look to that industry to drive some of
期待那个 行业 推动一些
the you know just computer systems
你 只 知道 计算机系统
really hardware and software systems
真正的硬件和软件系统
that we'll take we'll take our game to
我们将采取 我们将我们的游戏
the next level
下一个级别
just understanding on the algorithmic
只是理解算法
level or cognitive level is just to
水平 或认知水平只是 为了
understanding the learning the meaning
理解 学习的意义
of learning would be how to predict but
学习将是 如何预测，但
on the circuit level is different but at
在电路级别上有所不同但是在
the what level on the circuit level well
电路级别的水平如何
of course it's different right but
当然这是不同的，但是
already you I think you made a mistake
已经你 我 认为 你犯了一个错误
there honestly like you said the
老实说，就像你说的那样
cognitive level is learning how to
认知水平是学习如何
predict but I'm not sure what you mean
预测，但我不确定你的意思
by that there's many things you could
由 有你可以很多东西
mean and are what our cognitive science
意思是并且是 我们的认知 科学
is about is learning which of those
是关于学习哪些
versions like I don't think it's
像我这样的版本不 认为 它
learning how to predict
学习如何预测
I think it's learning what you need to
我认为这是学习你需要什么
know to plan actions and to a map you
知道计划的行动，并为 您的地图
know all those things like it's not just
知道所有这些 事情， 不仅仅是这样
about predicting it's because there are
关于预测 它是因为有
things we can imagine so that you would
我们 可以想象的 事情， 这样你就可以
never predict because there never happen
永远不会预测因为从未发生过
unless we somehow make the world
除非我们以某种方式创造世界
different so generalizations are you're
不同的，所以概括是 你
not predicting okay when your model
你的模特不能预测 好的
could generalize but especially in the
可以概括， 但特别是在
transfer learning that you are
转移学习你是谁
interested in a few hundred of neurons
感兴趣的 神经元的几百
in prefrontal cortex they have
在前额叶皮层他们有
generalize a lot yes but not kind of a
概括了许多是但不是一种
Bayesian model do that you said but a
你说的贝叶斯模型就是这样做 的
thean model won't do that or they don't
thean模型不 会这样做， 或者他们 不这样做
do it the way a Bayesian model does for
像贝叶斯模型那样做
sure because that's in the abstract
当然， 因为那是抽象的
level well I mean how do you really know
水平 很好我的意思是你怎么知道的
like and what does it mean to say that
像 它 有什么 意思是说，
some neurons do it like so maybe another
有些神经元会像其他神经元一样
way to put this is to say look we have a
把这个放的方式就是说我们 有一个
certain math that we use to capture
我们用来捕捉的某些数学
these you could call it abstract I call
这些你可以称之为抽象我打电话
it software level abstractions right I
它的软件层次的抽象的权利我
mean all engineering is based on some
意味着所有的工程都是基于一些
kind of abstraction but you might have a
一种 抽象的 ，但你可能有一个
circuit level abstraction a certain kind
电路级抽象某种
of hardware level that you're interested
您感兴趣的硬件级别
in describing the brain at and I'm
在描述大脑和我
mostly working out or starting from a
主要是锻炼或 从一个 开始
more software level of abstraction right
更多的软件抽象级别
they're all distractions we're not
他们都是 我们不喜欢的分心
talking about molecules here right we're
说起 这里的分子权 我们
talking about some abstract notion of
谈论一些 抽象的概念
maybe a circuit or of a program okay
也许是电路或程序没问题
right now it's a really interesting
现在它 真的很 有趣
question if I look at some circuits how
如果我看 一些电路怎么样的问题
do I know what program they're
我知道他们是什么节目吗？
implementing right if I look at the
如果我看一下，就实施权利
circuits in this machine could I tell
我能告诉 这 台机器的电路
what program they're implementing well
他们正在实施什么计划
maybe but certainly it would be a lot
也许但肯定会很多
easier if I knew something about what
如果我知道什么，我会更容易
programs they might
他们可能的计划
implementing before I start to look at
在我开始看之前实施
the circuitry if I just looked at the
电路，如果我只是看着
circuitry without knowing what a program
电路不知道什么是程序
was or what programs the thing might be
是什么程序或可能是什么程序
doing or what kind of programming
做什么或编程 什么
components would be mapable to circuits
组件可映射到电路
in different ways right I don't even
以不同的方式， 我甚至没有
know how to begin to answer that
知道如何开始回答这个问题
question
题
so I think you know we've made some
所以我想你知道我们做了一些
progress at understanding what neurons
了解什么神经元的进展
are doing in certain low-level parts of
正在做某些低级别的部分
sensory system and certain parts of the
感觉系统和某些部分
motor system like primary motor cortex
运动系统像初级运动皮层
like basically the parts of the neurons
像基本上是神经元的部分
that are closest to the inputs and
最接近输入和
outputs of the brain right where we
我们所处的大脑输出
don't eat when you can say we don't need
不吃饭的时候，你可以 说我们不需要
the kind of software abstractions that
那种软件抽象
I'm talking about or where we sort of
我说 的 还是我们 的 排序
agree on what those things already are
同意那些 已经存在的 东西
so we can make enough progress on
所以我们可以取得足够的 进展
knowing what to look for and how to how
知道要 寻找 什么 ，以及如何 如何
to know when we found it but if you want
要知道我们何时找到它，但如果你想要的话
to talk about flexible planning things
谈谈灵活的计划事情
that are more like cognition that you
这更像是对你的认知
know go on in prefrontal cortex right I
知道在前额叶皮质上继续吧
this point I don't I don't think that
这一点上我不，我不 认为
just by recording from those neurons
只是通过记录那些神经元
we're gonna be able to answer those
我们将 能够 回答 这些问题
questions in a meaningful engineering
在一个有意义的工程 问题
way a way that that any engineer
任何工程师的方式
software a hardware whatever could
软件无论如何都是硬件
really say yeah okay I get it I get
真的说是的好我得到 它 我 得到 它
those insights in a way that I can
那些见解以我能做到的方式
engineer with and that's what my goal is
与工程师，这就是我的目标是什么
right so my goal that's my goal to do at
对，所以我的目标是我的目标
the software level the hardware level or
软件级别硬件级别或
the entire systems level connecting them
连接它们的整个系统级别
and I think that you know we can do that
而且我想 你知道我们可以做到 这一点
by taking what we're doing and bringing
通过我们正在做的和带来
into contact with people studying neural
与研究神经的人接触
circuits but I don't think you can you
电路，但我认为你不能
can leave this level out and just go
可以离开这个级别， 然后去
straight to the neural circuits and I
直接到 神经回路和我
think the more you have the more
认为你拥有的越多
progress we make the more we can help
我们取得的进步越多，我们就能提供帮助
people who are studying at the neural
谁 是在神经学 人
circuit level and they can help us
电路级别，他们可以帮助我们
address these other engineering
解决这些其他工程
questions that we don't really have
我们没有真正拥有的问题
access to like the power issue or the
访问权力问题或
speed issue thank you okay thanks that
速度问题谢谢你好， 谢谢
was great I thought maybe it'd give
很棒，我想也许它会给予
Jessica Han
杰西卡韩
[Applause]
[掌声]